<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop - The best freelance job leads emailed to you daily.</title>
    <description>Get over 200+ hand selected freelance web consulting leads sent to your inbox every week</description>
    <link>http://letsworkshop.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://letsworkshop.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 14:41:30 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 14:41:30 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to build a profitable sales funnel</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-off-what-is-a-sales-funnel&quot;&gt;First off, what is a sales funnel?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process that every freelance project goes through to land you a paying client. This includes how you win and find work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-most-sales-funnels-look-like&quot;&gt;What do most sales funnels look like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every freelancer’s sales funnel is identical. You find a client online or through referral and proceed with a disorganized, inconsistent courting process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-inquiry&quot;&gt;Pre-inquiry&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is where a client or freelancer find one another. This can happen in a variety of places, like your portfolio, a website, referral or job posting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;inquiry&quot;&gt;Inquiry&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is usually an &lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot; class=&quot;off-site&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://letsworkshop.com/phone-calls&quot;&gt;phone call&lt;/a&gt; made expressing interest in working together. Typically, this is inquiry is pretty short and simple, containing contact information and a little background on the project or freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;inquiry-review&quot;&gt;Inquiry Review&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The freelancer and client will each assess whatever information they’ve been given about working together, and if desired, schedule some sort of follow up meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;first-meeting&quot;&gt;First Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The freelancer and client meet over Skype, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsworkshop.com/phone-calls&quot;&gt;phone call&lt;/a&gt;, or in person to discuss the project. Both sides give a rough idea of what they’re looking for, and receive a solid understanding of what working together will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Usually you, the freelancer, will sit down to put together some sort of proposal that will put ink to paper about what is expected.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-review&quot;&gt;Proposal Review&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The client will receive your roadmap and possibly ask to refine/change it. This is usually a string of emails, questions, and back-and-forth about the project until most details are ironed out.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;revised-proposal-if-asked-to-change-first-proposal&quot;&gt;Revised Proposal (if asked to change first proposal):&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The freelancer will either present or send over a revised proposal. This may include a contract and invoice, at which point the client will either accept, decline, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsworkshop.com/freelancer-negotiation&quot;&gt;negotiate&lt;/a&gt; a lower rate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-actual-work&quot;&gt;The actual work&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is when you will begin work on the project, usually starting by learning as much as possible about the project and company you’re working with. Once you have adequately researched the project, you’ll begin creating the deliverables you and the client agreed upon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-i-improve-my-sales-funnel&quot;&gt;How can I improve my sales funnel?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to improve your sales funnel you must first identify what each step of the process looks like for you. Some freelancers might get most of their inquiries from referrals, others might use job boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve identified how your sales funnel is unique, you can identify where the problems are, like at what step potential clients are dropping off. Here are some good questions to start:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step are you deciding whether to take on a project?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Is there a better point in the sales funnel to do this?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step is a client’s decision to hire you made?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At what step do you want a client to make their decision?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step do you think you’re ready to give a price quote?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Have you ever given a price before this step?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If so, how can you ensure this doesn’t happen?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you putting too much importance on any one step? (hint: it’s step 8)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you eliminate as many steps as possible without losing clients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/sales-funnel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/sales-funnel</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to make 2x more than other freelancers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Freelancers tend to beat around the bush when it comes to money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s common to ask “what’s your hourly rate?” when what you’re really interested in knowing is how much a freelancer makes (and particularly how much more/less they make than you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An hourly rate can be deceptive. All it gives you is a number. You’re left to piece how much they actually make, where they find work, and other important questions alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s one of the reasons I surveyed hundreds of freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My survey asked three basic questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much do you make per month?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you do when you run out of work?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much of your work comes from each source?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;border-cell-only&quot; style=&quot;margin: 4em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;th colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
			The average freelancer based on survey results...
		&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			earns &lt;strong&gt;$3,590&lt;/strong&gt; USD a month before taxes
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			gets &lt;strong&gt;2.46&lt;/strong&gt; inquiries from their website per month
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			makes &lt;strong&gt;61%&lt;/strong&gt; of their income from referrals
		&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;border-row-only&quot; style=&quot;margin: 4em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;When out of work they...&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;th&gt;Percent&lt;/th&gt;		
		&lt;th&gt;Income&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;th&gt;Difference&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;

	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Email prospects&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;12%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$5,515&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td class=&quot;good&quot;&gt;+91%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
		
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Look for work on a job board or marketplace&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$3,257&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;+13%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;

	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Turn to their social media or network&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;40%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$2,920&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;+1%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Do nothing or wait&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;24%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$2,316&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td class=&quot;bad&quot;&gt;-20%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results-were-clear-the-people-who-went-directly-to-prospects-by-emailing-them-made-almost-2x-more-than-everybody-else&quot;&gt;The results were clear: the people who went directly to prospects by emailing them made almost 2X more than everybody else.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, twice as many freelancers do nothing during a dry spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why do only 12% of people go direct, when it’s clear it works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is it that it takes a lot more work to do outreach and when you’re used to billing hundreds of dollars for an hour of your time – spending that much time on something else besides billable work just isn’t the best use of your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why the rest of the course below will walk you through how to make this process 10x faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/earnings</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/earnings</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to double your cold email response rate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of freelancers get hung up on what they should say to a new prospect they’re cold emailing. Staring at a blank screen can be a horrible feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’ve developed this cold email checklist after studying thousands of emails and why they got ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to just dive in and write a quick, short rough draft email to your prospect. For more help with that, check out my book: &lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot;&gt;Emails That Win You Clients&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;once-you-have-your-first-draft-email-written-you-can-apply-a-few-quick-rules-to-it-to-make-sure-youre-maximizing-your-response-rate&quot;&gt;Once you have your first draft email written, you can apply a few quick rules to it to make sure you’re maximizing your response rate:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/subject.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The subject line should be so specific it could only be sent to one person in the world.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will make sure your email gets opened because busy people look to remove spam first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/length.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The length of a cold email should be under 120 words.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Busy people don&#39;t have time to read much. Make it simple, crisp, and get to the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/value.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Your email should provide something of value.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Would you be happy to receive this email, even if you had no intention of hiring someone? Delivering advice or tips is an easy way to show you&#39;re on the client&#39;s side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/social.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Don&#39;t include links to your social media or portfolio.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;A prospective client doesn&#39;t really care about your work... at least not yet. The only point of this first email is to get them to reply so making them click on your website, linkedin profile or portfolio doesn&#39;t help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/clarity.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; It should be easy to find the point of your email.
	&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Someone using a job board probably has a lot of email responses and is more likely to scan and look for the next step. Make that part of your email easy to find. Bold it if you have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/reply.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The end of your email should be easy to reply to in seconds.
	&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t want to give a busy lead more work. If the lead can say &quot;sounds good&quot; you&#39;re probably on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-your-email-passes-all-of-these-rules-it-is-probably-ready-to-send-and-youll-have-a-30-50-chance-of-response-form-a-client&quot;&gt;If your email passes all of these rules, it is probably ready to send and you’ll have a 30-50% chance of response form a client.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You still have to land one of them. So how do yoy find a list of prospects you can email right now?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/cold-emails</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/cold-emails</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use job boards to find hundreds of leads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I started a service that finds hundreds of freelance leads for a small group of ambitious consultants specializing in design and development work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group uses my leads to earn hundreds of thousands of dollars every year. Yet, 99% of them are available for free online. In fact, anyone could find them and land the same projects for free all by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hiding this, I’m going to walk you through exactly how I find leads every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-post-it-note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note about Workshop:&lt;/strong&gt; If you don&#39;t want to do this all yourself, you too can use my service to skip everything below and just have it done for you. You&#39;ll jump straight to the part where you have a limitless amount of amazing freelance projects in your email every day. Just sayin. &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Try Workshop today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heres-how-to-use-job-boards-to-find-an-endless-supply-of-leads-each-month&quot;&gt;Here’s how to use job boards to find an endless supply of leads each month:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-gather-your-supplies&quot;&gt;Step 1: Gather your supplies.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patience and perseverance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An RSS reader.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few hours a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-search-for-freelance-job-boards-and-compile-them-into-an-rss-feed-reader&quot;&gt;Step 2: Search for freelance job boards and compile them into an RSS feed reader.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to find high quality job board on the web and compile their RSS feed into an RSS reader (I recommend feedly). If you want to skip this part and just get to the Step 3 you can download my Instant Lead Generator below and plug it into your favorite RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;featured-product&quot; style=&quot;border-top: 1px solid #888; border-bottom: 1px solid #888; padding: 2em .5em; font-size: 80%; margin: 3em 0;&quot;&gt;
	
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/instant-lead-generator.png&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 30%; margin: .5em 1em 5em 0;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;display: table;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: .5em 0;&quot;&gt;Instant Lead Generator&lt;/h3&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;This file will save you hundreds of hours of work. Simply plug it into any RSS reader and enjoy thousands of freelance job opportunities at your fingertips. It would take you a really long time to compile this list of job boards on your own. I&#39;ve spent years compiling this list and searching high and low in every nook and cranny of the web to build this monster.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;This file comes pre-loaded for you with a huge chunk of job boards. It&#39;s what I use to find thousands of high-quality freelance leads for Workshop. You&#39;ll get a ready to go OPML file that you just need to import into an RSS RSS reader to instantly monitor every job board that houses freelance leads.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;$19.95&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com/l/instant-leads&quot; class=&quot;buy-link&quot; style=&quot;width: 6em; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Buy now&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-browse-the-rss-feeds-and-pick-the-low-hanging-fruit-first&quot;&gt;Step 3: Browse the RSS feeds and pick the low-hanging fruit first.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for projects that look like ideal fits first. I recommend starting with established job boards like Authentic Jobs and Behance. When it comes to this, getting started is half the battle. Don’t think you have to find hundreds of people to email every day. Instead, be consistent about finding 1 or 2 new opportunities daily. This should only take minutes to create a constant flow of warm prospects coming into your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that ultimately it’s a numbers game, and burning out by contacting a billion leads on your first day won’t produce great results. Once you pick the 1 or 2 low-hanging, most desirable projects, contact them immediately. Later you can go back and find more if you have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you open up feedly and see one or two project you’d like to work on, contact those before moving on. Here’s a video of me doing this process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7hHlh3yKUp0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro-tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Use additional search criteria when available, terms like ‘remote’ and ‘freelance’ will skip all the location-specific or full-time listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-find-niche-job-boards-that-apply-to-your-specialty&quot;&gt;Step 4: Find niche job boards that apply to your specialty.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some job boards don’t offer an RSS feed. This means you have to go through their site by hand. While more time consuming, these sites are the home of some of the best freelance projects - especially if they relate to something you specialize in. To cut down on time, get familiar with where each job board keeps important details like location preference, budgets, and project type. Building up a familiarity with these niche job boards takes time, but there are so many new job boards popping up that there are constant opportunities to land work. Don’t look for ideal clients, instead look for people that need a problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s some examples of niche job boards:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=seeking%20freelancer&amp;amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&quot;&gt;Hacker news seeking freelancer threads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://larajobs.com&quot;&gt;LaraJobs for PHP, Laravel jobs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://djangojobbers.com/&quot;&gt;Django jobbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.railsjobs.com/&quot;&gt;Rails Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gotten the hang of this process and begin to land work consistently from job boards, you’ll find that it really doesn’t require you doing the work. In fact, since your hourly rate is pretty high it not make sense for you to do this entire thing yourself anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hell, even if you’ve never done it yourself and want to skip the learning curve of curating and hand-picking leads from job boards, and get straight to the awesome part high quality consistent freelance leads, you’ll want to outsource it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could hire a general purpose VA for $500/month+ or you could pay Workshop (my highly specialized service) to do it for you for a fraction of cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save 4-5 hours a week and just get the best consulting opportunities on the web delivered to your inbox! Starting at only $99/month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, using the steps outlined above you can generate steady client work just using job boards. This 1-on-1 outreach is powerful because you don’t have to rely on outside forces to win work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;now-that-you-have-hundreds-of-leads-at-your-fingertips-you-might-be-wondering-how-to-keep-track-of-it-all-thats-what-well-cover-next&quot;&gt;Now that you have hundreds of leads at your fingertips, you might be wondering how to keep track of it all. That’s what we’ll cover next:&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/using-job-boards</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/using-job-boards</guid>
        
        <category>finding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use Twitter to find leads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’re probably not friends with the hundreds of people who turn to twitter looking for help on projects everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why the most common thing freelancers do when they want to find work VIA Twitter yields no results. It’s usually tweeting something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I’m available for projects!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey guy - I’m looking for freelancer work..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;help … someone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach is like expecting to find your next client by yelling into an echo-y cave with no one in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, if you wanted to find the love of your life and had no clue where they lived, who they were, or anything about them you probably wouldn’t post a notice at a supermarket saying seeking love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead a sounder approach would be to actually approach someone who appears to be a match, directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: you might text or call someone who gives you their number. You might approach someone at a bar or a dating website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are better options than the grocery store posting because they’re going to where the fish are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of expecting fate to intervene, you’re giving yourself the best chance. You should do the same with twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why post in your empty silo that is your twitter audience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, If you want to harness the power of twitter, try using something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://topsy.com&quot;&gt;Topsy&lt;/a&gt;. Searching through all the clutter on twitter can take hours and you probably wont find very much via their default search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, a service like Topsy can help you customize and sort your search more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to using words like freelance, design, and development - add words like “email” (to find people who leave behind an email address). Follow up with them over email instead of just on twitter. You can also set reminders and notifications via google alerts or tweetdeck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to sort through the multitudes of tweets out there by finding keywords people use when tweeting out for help and approaching them directly in a one to one setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not expecting your desperate tweets to bring in work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/market-twitter</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/market-twitter</guid>
        
        <category>market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to respond to RFPs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any RFP I’m interested in, I ask them one simple question. If they can answer it directly, I’ll move forward. If not, I move on. In the last year, I’ve responded to two formal RFPs. I lost both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth of RFPs is they’re usually written with an agency in mind. I know, I’ve been the guy they were written for before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RFPs are an interesting animal. From my experience, most of the marketing folks involved with sending an RFP out for bid don’t even want to do it… they have to. I have a rather pleasant ongoing contract with a large state organization in PA, and they were smart enough to use their 1-year extension option with my contract to avoid having to send this out for bid yearly. Every other year, however, they are required by the state auditor general to do this RFP crap… just like every other state funded organization in PA. They don’t have to choose by price, and in the end they get to make the final call so long as it fit’s their budget plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Kurt Elster said, the RFPs are written with someone particular in mind for the job (me). It’s nice to be on the inside of that situation, but they are difficult to respond to for folks on the outside looking in. Sometimes you just get lucky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, when it comes to RFPs, I always weigh the value of the project against the time and hassle involved. If it’s an ongoing contract, I usually give it a little more consideration. I’m a big fan of guaranteed income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moral of the story is that hatred for the RFP is mutual in a lot of instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Corey Tiani&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people who do the best with RFP’s (and are actually the people who’ve made $100k+ from workshop) are the ones who have a system in place for replying to RFP’s specifically. They either hire someone to help, or have developed such a templated and refined process that they can do it themselves in a fraction of the time. This usually means they see it as a numbers game and don’t sweat it when they don’t hear back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/requests-for-proposals</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/requests-for-proposals</guid>
        
        <category>market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use masterminds as a freelancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a member of Workshop’s Mastermind group, I’ve shared knowledge, business practices, and what’s working for my businesses with other freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, four of us in the Mastermind group got to chat via Google Hangout and swap some stories. It was such a unique opportunity to sit down and chat with other designers and developers… something that unfortunately doesn’t happen all that often. I think we all get so busy with our work and what we’re producing that we forget to reach out and connect with others in our industry – and that’s perhaps one of the most important things we were lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started by introducing ourselves and how we got to where we currently are in our business. We had a variety of skill levels, from someone doing front-end development for about a year to a back-end developer who had been going since 1999. We talked about our ideal clients, what we’re working on now (and how it’s going), and what challenges we’re facing in our businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed how we can improve our skills and really hone our craft to become better designers and developers. I’m really looking forward to getting to know these guys and sharing what I learn from working with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Alex,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across your website on twitter and I really love your work. You’ve been behind so many of my favorite designs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a freelance designer and illustrator as well, but I’ve struggled to find new clients lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you mind sharing a few tips on how you would look for new work (if you were starting out)? I’m always curious about how fantastic designers do things and 1 or 2 minutes of your time would be insanely valuable to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make: I hate networking. Most networking events leave me feeling somewhere between “so unclean I need to take a shower clothed” and “there isn’t enough xanax in the world to be cool right now.” Okay, I’m exaggerating, but networking events are rough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for people like me, mastermind groups are the ultimate networking hack. A mastermind group is a group of like-minded individual who meet regularly (usually once a week) to help each other out. Mastermind groups are even better when the people involved are from the same industry, working toward a common purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to have Rob, reach out to me, and ask if I’d like to help run a new mastermind group for Workshop. Rob and I have bounced idea’s off each other before, and as usual, I thought it was a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastermind groups have three great purposes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;PROBLEM SOLVING: Any question you ask, can be potentially solved by the group as a whole. Businesspeople and freelancers often feel like they’re going it alone, the mastermind group is also a support group. Even if they can’t solve a problem, the group can at least work out next steps to solve a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;ACCOUNTABILITY: Every meeting closes with sharing each member sharing a goal they’d like to accomplish. The next week, they have to report to the group the status of that goal. Being held accountable is a powerful motivational tool that entrepreneurs often miss out on there own.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;NETWORKING: Everyone’s combined connections become the group’s total networking power. Have a problem that I know my colleague can solve? I’ll introduce you. That spirit of fraternal collaboration empowers the group.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this isn’t my first mastermind group, this was my first meeting with the Workshop Sales Funnel Mastermind group, and I’ve already come with new business contacts, new friends, and even some actionable advice to promote my business. I’m looking forward to future conversation with the group, I can’t wait to see what we accomplish together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/masterminds</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/masterminds</guid>
        
        <category>finding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use Google search to find leads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;run-in&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;G&lt;/span&gt;oogle is one of the best ways to find leads&lt;/span&gt; but freelancers rarely use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Google indexes a ton of opportunities that you can find by tweaking a few key search settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re interested in responding to &lt;a href=&quot;http://letsworkshop.com/requests-for-proposals&quot;&gt;RFP’s&lt;/a&gt;, you can search: &lt;strong&gt;“RFP website design development filetype:PDF”&lt;/strong&gt; to only show PDF documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, you can set your search range to just the “past week” to only get recent, relevant results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no limit to the amount of links you’ll find on google, so getting specific with keywords, budget, search options, and anything else you can is really going to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=RFP+website+design+development+filetype:PDF&amp;amp;num=50&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;es_sm=91&amp;amp;biw=1521&amp;amp;bih=1080&amp;amp;source=lnt&amp;amp;tbs=qdr:w&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=mAUSVZ-hIYjToATr0IDACA&amp;amp;ved=0CBQQpwU&quot;&gt;Here’s what a google search with those settings looks like.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/google-search</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/google-search</guid>
        
        <category>market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to get responses from ignored emails</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s an email I picked up from Blair Enns. It’s revived cold leads, dead deals, and gotten responses to ignored emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I haven’t heard back from you on [project/opportunity] so I’m going to assume you’ve gone in a different direction or your priorities have changed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use it pretty regularly. it works because it makes it clear to the recipient that you’ve moved on. Since people are loss averse, their natural inclination is to say “Wait!” and open the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it out. I’m sure you have sales leads you haven’t heard back from. Email them this and see what they say. You have nothing to lose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/the-magic-email</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/the-magic-email</guid>
        
        <category>winning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use Behance to find work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Behance has some of the world’s top companies coming to it for websites and design work. Additionally, all of the bidding happens through the Behance application process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually recommend you try to circumvent the behance application (or applications that happen through a specific job board).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually there will be enough on the job posting page for you to track down the people making the decision and contact them via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s a blog, twitter account, or something else try googling the heck out of the company you’re interested in applying for. It’s amazing how easy you can find emails like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, send a supplemental email to the lead in addition to your behance (or job board specific) application. If you’re scared the person might not like that you went the extra effort to connect with them, don’t be. If anything you may consider pointing out that you’ve gone the extra mile in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/behance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/behance</guid>
        
        <category>market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
