<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop - Get great clients sent to you everyday</title>
    <description>Get over 200+ hand selected freelance web consulting leads sent to your inbox every week</description>
    <link>http://letsworkshop.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://letsworkshop.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 13:40:35 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 13:40:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swipe: Workshop annual upgrade email that resulted in $15k spike</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an email I used to create a huge spike in revenue. I want to use it in the future to create an evergreen annual upgrade email. Think about how you can use something like this with your clients to create a hard-to-resist offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scott&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I hope you’re doing well. I’m emailing you because there’s a couple urgent matters I gotta touch base with you on. not everyone is getting this email.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;First off did you know you’re about to lose out on $689?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The current pricing for Workshop is $99/month and it’s about to go up in price again as I release some big improvements and additional features to Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Right now you can upgrade to yearly billing for $499 but I won’t be offering this price once the new features kick in. That means you can lock-in your Workshop subscription at this $41/month introductory price forever right now. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I don’t normally send an email like this if you’re on monthly billing but because of the coming improvements to Workshop i need to let you know what you’ll be missing out on so you can make a truly informed decision about whether you should commit to Workshop for a year.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s also why what’s coming is so exciting to me it’s all designed to land you more work and end dry spells - and it’s about to be released very soon (in June/July)- you’ll be able to:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Turn off categories that you’re not interested in so you don’t waste even a second.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Track your progress by making sure you’re hitting milestones like emailing leads, getting replies, and winning clients.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Have your own personal email specialist (Julie) find leads that match your specialty, and help you land them by writing emails for you and keeping you accountable.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Use Workshop to land referral work by sending leads to your friends in one-click.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Automated follow up reminders when you have a warm lead to make sure you never forget to follow up.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Access to twice as many premium leads now that I run Folyo.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;All of this stuff will be released in the next 2 weeks and all of this is going to make it easier for you to find work.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Like i said already the new features will also come with an increase in price and a cap on the amount of members we take in. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s why this is sorta urgent.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;If you’d like to upgrade to yearly billing and save $689 on your subscription each year and lock-in this rate forever, use this link to upgrade now.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you have any questions you can just hit “reply” or call me personally at 760-693-3360.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Looking forward to having you as a customer!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Regards,
Robert&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/swipe/2017/06/05/workshop-upgrade-email.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/swipe/2017/06/05/workshop-upgrade-email.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>swipe</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who to hire first</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hire copy first, design second, code third&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words are design. If you’re hiring someone to design your site, they should start with words. If they don’t or they can’t than you should hire someone else. If you have a designer already but they don’t know how to write copy you may want to reconsider that designer. Until then, hire a copywriter. Make every design go through the copywriter before it gets to the designer. Likewise, your website, your app, or your software should all go through the designer before it gets to the developer. You can’t develop something soundly without sound design in place first. Development is also design. It’s all design really. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/hiring/2017/06/05/who-to-hire-first.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/hiring/2017/06/05/who-to-hire-first.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hiring</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s the most important aspect to the sales process?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;OK so a lot of people think writing a great cold email and being the first person to contact a client is the key to outreach email. However, the true is actually following up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to break down why that is then talk about what you can do to dominate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First let’s imagine a John C. Client posts a job on a job board. He’s pretty into the project as he writes his job board and so he’s at the peak of his interest during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He finishes his job post and posts it. He has a meeting in 15 minutes. So he’s only able to look at the first few replies that start coming in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s flip over to Freelancer A: Cindy Email Skills and Freelancer B: Kevin Followup. Cindy writes great emails and is focused on being on of the first people to reply to a listing. To do this she saves time by sending the same email to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin on the other hand is more focused on following up. He replies later and just makes sure to keep bugging his leads until he hears back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who do you think wins in this scenario?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy might have the initial advantage. While John C. Client is sitting at his computer, he may see Cindy’s email and reply to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since Cindy isn’t focused on following up, if he doesn’t see or respond to her email in the first 15 minutes after posting the job post, John is a lot less likely to ever respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he gets back from his meeting, there will now be dozens and dozens of replies to his job posting. He’s much less likely to see Cindy’s job post at that point, since it’s gone to the bottom of his inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on the other hand Kevin Followup waits to send his first email. He sends it in the next day even. Now it’s true that John C. Client is less focused on his job listing the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s simply less interested. However, when he’s going through the emails in his inbox, Kevin’s email is closer to the top so there’s a higher chance he get seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, they don’t call him Kevin Followup for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 days later, after John C. Client has replied to a few of the initial batch of emails, including Cindy Email Skills, Kevin Followup sends his second email following up. John C Client notices the email and just doesn’t have time to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something’s come up in his department at work which needs all hands on deck for the next few weeks. The hiring project is put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy sees the email response from John C. Client  and crafts an amazing followup response. She details her vision of the project, what she would do with it, and how she would implement her expertise. She spends a few hours on writing an amazing letter and sends it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Cindy drops off. Because John got so busy he doesn’t have time to reply to Cindy, even to let her know that he’s busy for the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy gets despondent about the client and shrugs and says “that’s just freelancing I guess”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand Kevin Followup continues with sending brief followups to the john C every 5 days. He doesn’t spend any time on them he’s just consistent about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After his 4th followup (20 days into the initial reply) with no response Kevin decides he will close the loop with John. He sends a final email saying “since I haven’t heard from you I have to assume your priorities have changed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 days into the posting his job post, John C. Finally has a chance to pull his head out of the water and check back on the replies to his job post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chaos is finally taken care of and he’s finally ready to go through some of the  replies. In the past week only Kevin Followup has emailed him about the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, his last 3 emails are ALL from Kevin. Realizing he’s now about to lose out on even Kevin, John quickly follows up with the last email from Kevin and they begin discussing the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this isn’t how every single project happens. There are varying degrees. However, I hop I’ve illustrated that following up is much more important than just sending on email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is a lot of projects don’t happen at once. There’s different varying degrees. Some even take longer than John C.’S project (and we’ll talk about how to stay on a client’s radar for these type of projects that may take MONTHS to develop in the next lesson)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, THIS is the dirty truth that’s the reality of how projects happen. It’s about maintaining the relationship, being the last one standing. Because the truth is most people won’t continue to followup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of being one email in a crowded inbox of two dozen freelancers. You’ll be the only one all alone. This is part of YOUR job. It’s not the client’s problem to make sure YOU follow up. It’s completely on you. The good news is 90% of people won’t. Reap the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/sales/2017/06/05/whats-the-most-important-aspect-of-sales-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/sales/2017/06/05/whats-the-most-important-aspect-of-sales-process.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sales</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The #1 thing to do if you need work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The best way land work in the next 15 minutes, that no one else does&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to use outreach to attract clients rather than chase after them.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey friend,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been thinking about where I want to take Workshop in 2016. One idea I’ve been tossing around for a long time is a more hands-on version of the service, where I not only send leads - but even send emails on my clients behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That way you literally have clients coming to you without lifting a finger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even with me doing your outreach for you you still wouldn’t see results right away most likely - so I started to ask myself what I could do at the beginning to bring these clients big results quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(After all, this new service would cost a lot more than the current Workshop subscription, so I’d need to make it profitable from day one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what would I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I’d do for my clients is follow up with ALL of their past clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve observed in my business as well as my friends businesses that this is without a doubt the #1 most unused tactic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re always on the look out for more work. So much so that you forget to follow up with past clients, the people most likely to hire you. Even my extremely successful freelancing friends admit as much. When I shared the idea they said: “Rob, I NEVER FOLLOW UP WITH CLIENTS. If you had something that would help with that I’d throw money at you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while the premium concierge service is in the works, I have something to share with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number 1 thing I would do if I was in your shoes right now to generate more revenue in 2016 is one thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email all of your clients from the past 2-3 years (you can even go beyond this) and write them a simple message. Say the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey [first name], just wanted to follow up and see how your business is doing. Is there anything I can do to help grow your business? Give me a call if you need help :)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Talk soon, 
[Your name]
[Your Phone Number]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter if you recently spoke to the client or if you haven’t touched base with them in the past 3 weeks. Send this email. You won’t regret it, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your clients won’t be annoyed. They will think you are helpful and considerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of all it works. You’ll line up work and you’ll find creating repeat clients so much easier than creating new clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you do this once, make it habit. Set a reminder to follow up with every single client again in 3 months. That’s how you create a recurring stream of clients coming to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it for today. Report back with your results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/referrals/2017/06/05/what-to-do-if-you-need-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/referrals/2017/06/05/what-to-do-if-you-need-work.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>referrals</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Re-activation email copy from VA staff finder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an email sent to me 6(?) months after I used their service. It felt like a nice way to touch back with someone who had used their service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently don’t do this enough, so I want to use this email as a way to follow-up with past customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We hope you’re doing well. Over the last week we’ve collated a solid list of all our ‘hot’ (meaning very experienced!) virtual staff that are currently looking for work by teaming up with Virtual Staff Finder.
Here’s a list of all the qualified ‘experienced’ VAs:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Podcast Editor 2 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Audio/Video Editor 10 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Web Developer 8&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Web Designer 7&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Graphic Designer 10&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Copy Writer/Content Writer 4&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	High-End SEO 8 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Digital Marketer 10 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Ecommerce VA 8&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Project Manager 12&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Bookkeeper 8&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Executive Assistant 6&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	General Virtual Assistant 90 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And - these are all experienced staff, waiting to be hired.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’re currently looking to hire for any of the roles above, simply hop onto the site and sign-up - one of our Relationship Managers will be in touch with you as soon as your order comes through and you’ll be well on your way to hiring the VA you need to help run, support and growing your staff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reply to this email - we’re here to help!
Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Team VSF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/swipe/2017/06/05/va-staff-finder-template.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/swipe/2017/06/05/va-staff-finder-template.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>swipe</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Template: Utilize your network</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey [Name],
Did I tell you I’ve started doing freelance web design? Check out my portfolio here (list free sites or personal projects).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know how connected you are to creative entrepreneurs, so I’m wondering if you knew anyone who may need a website? I can even sweeten the deal for you by offering you a finders fee as a token of my gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/referrals/2017/06/05/utilize-your-network.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/referrals/2017/06/05/utilize-your-network.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>referrals</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating upsells</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating upsell opportunities through outstanding on boarding
⁃	What do most freelancers and agencies do when a client pays?
⁃	They do the work and then forget about them
⁃	They don’t follow up
⁃	They don’t check in
⁃	They’re off looking for more work
⁃	They’ve done the hard part: landed a great client
⁃	And yet they just walk away like it’s nothing
⁃	Instead what I want you to do is automate a great experience for them. 
⁃	Have every single client pay through the same form.
⁃	There’s a bunch of different ones but I recommend Hiveage, it’s the way my contractors pay me. 
⁃	Connect this payment form to a drip campaign that will follow up with them indefinitely every three months. 
⁃	Send the 10k email
⁃	
⁃	Send checkins and follow ups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rob, Howdy! How’re things going with Workshop? Been a while since we chatted, figured I’d reach out. Take care, nickd! http://nickd.org https://draft.nuPushing current and existing clients to this contact form when they need more work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be one of your highest performing campaigns you’ve ever created and yet it’s dead simple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	The email course drip campaign that will sell clients with long sales cycles
⁃	A lot of freelancers complain about long sales cycles this is when it takes a client months or sometimes years to decide on a project.
⁃	That’s because they do it wrong
⁃	Let me introduce email courses 
⁃	Few freelancers use them, yet they’re a great tool for delivering value
⁃	A client signs up to one
⁃	Automatically they’re sent articles you’ve written that deliver them value
⁃	As they receive these articles, they trust you
⁃	You are now the authority on these topics in their mind
⁃	Suddenly no one can compete with you
⁃	You’re able to sell every aspect of your expertise
⁃	All of the knowledge you’ve accumulated
⁃	All of the value you have in your head can now be transferred and presented to the client
⁃	All those rushed emails, sales calls, and more that you thought you didn’t really get a chance to say how you would help perfectly
⁃	Now you can with email courses
⁃	A client gets to build trust with you
⁃	So that when it’s time to buy there’s no hard sell
⁃	It’s just a client that KNOWS they’re getting a return on their investment
⁃	This how you create ideal clients&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	How to write an email course focused on delivering value and selling your services
⁃	HOW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	How to get clients signed up to your email course&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	How to get traffic funneled to your email course and contact form
⁃	Use your blog
⁃	Use your email signature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	How to automate a upsells into your client on boarding&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/upsells/2017/06/05/upsells.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/upsells/2017/06/05/upsells.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>upsells</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Typography for freelancers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s two things at the heart of design. Copywriting, and typography. Unsurprisingly both of these deal with words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words are what our live revolve around. Think about the last time you bought, consumed, or enjoyed something. It’s very likely words were involved at some point in presenting this thing to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presenting the thing to you is what design is about. You can’t get to the buying, consuming or enjoying until you’ve been presented with words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure color, shapes, images, and all of these graphical elements play a role. But what we’re really trying to shape is words. Even a purely graphical design is trying to convey words you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s getting kind of abstract. Let’s take a real example. Your clients. Throughout their engagement with you, they’re going to be confronted with words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words you’ve created. These words are what will decide whether they buy from you, are happy with the work, or hate your guts and ask for a refund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever done some of your finest work in your career – only to feel nervous when it’s time to present to the client? (Worse, have you ever had that work rejected by the client?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that? If your work is so great why isn’t it enough to win over the client on it’s own?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day the work doesn’t matter if you can’t get sell your ideas. You do that with words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So have you looked at the words you’ve used with clients lately? Are you calling them out or are you just going through the motions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you’re speaking  – is it because you’ve chosen it specifically – or because it’s just the way you think you should?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the words on your website, in your emails, in your email signature, the words you use on sales calls, in your proposals – how are they helping present you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then comes the next questions – beyond even the content of these words, how are you presenting these words graphically. Are they all legible? Are they easy to read? Does their hierarchy make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or are you sending a 5000 word, un-formatted, rambling and 8 pt font sized hard to read email? (Didn’t realize that typography happens even in an email?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you choosing each word you write? Are you choosing how to present these words?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not, you might be losing on one of the most important decisions you make in whether your business gets and finds clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Typography doesn’t matter.”
“Copywriting doesn’t matter.”
“Design doesn’t matter.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/sales/2017/06/05/typography-for-freelancers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/sales/2017/06/05/typography-for-freelancers.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sales</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Re-writing a headline</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My website’s design is beautiful, but it isn’t growing my business.
Elliot responded to my 2-minute design challenge email a few weeks ago because his website, Brightalyze, was in need of some help.
It receives compliments left and right, but is not converting — and the project was losing money as a result.
It’s a classic example of how design is not always the most important thing when it comes to web projects. That facts are; 90% of the web is type — and although the site was sleek and pretty, it was still out of touch with the pain-points of people visiting the site.
Since most people visiting a website will only ever see the headline, that’s what we’ll be focusing on when discussing how to improve this site.
It does a great job of looking like an established and trust-worthy company, both benefits of good branding. However, branding does not inspire people to try out a service, it only makes you not discount the company immediately.
Ultimately what will cause people to try the service is the offering.
The headline reads, “Create the World’s Next Great App”.
And the sub-head supports with, “Brightalyze helps with challenges of development, so you can relax.”
At first, these two sentences seem like they’re answering solid pain points for the user. However, if we dig a little deeper the truth is they are both quite vague.
For example, we don’t get answers to how will Brightalyze do these things, and why are they better than an established competitor at doing these things? We don’t even get answers to what exactly the service is, is it an iphone app, a web app, an online course, a concierge service etc.?
I didn’t know the answer to these questions either, so I asked Elliot. His response was, “We provide project management to incubate the project, that other services do not.”
That is actually a great selling point, and valuable service, much better than saying a blanket generic statement about ‘creating the world’s next great app’.
However, it’s not answering what pain it is solving.
So, how do you find what pain your product is solving? Would you believe me if I said that great wallet-bursting copywriting doesn’t happen in your head? It actually comes from your clients mouths. They are constantly talking about what they like and don’t like in public places (especially online).
To find this you simply need to search for the pain. It could be a reddit thread on r/freelance, it could be the comments of a blog article, it could even be in conversation with a client… but one of the best places to find these pain quotes is Amazon.
If you look at books on your topic, than look at the reviews for that book (particularly the 5 star and 1 star sections) you will find a great list of pains and delights that you can reverse-engineer to create beautiful copy.
The best part is you wont have to do too much work to make the messages resonate with your customer, because you are already using their words!
A quick Amazon review query resulted in various different pain points for freelance design clients, including:
	•	“I spent hours sifting through hundreds of Dribbble profiles”
	•	“When you work with a freelancer, you’re gambling.”
	•	“I just can’t relax and trust them.”
	•	“Design is often a failed effort at organizations.”
	•	“Finding a designer was like mining for gold.”
	•	“Design is a differentiating factor, but I just can’t nail it”
	•	“You hire a guy to design your website… and three months later nothing.”
How’s that for pain? Who knew the design profession was causing so many late nights for so many people. There’s literally thousands more pain points on amazon just waiting to me mined.
What do all of these pains deal with? Uncertainty. Stress. Trust. Time-wasting.
These are all things that Brightalyze can help with. Does “Create the World’s Next Great App” get that across? No.
I’ll be sending Elliot my suggestions for what the headline should say, but I also want to hear from you. If this was your site, what would you say in your headline?
How would you combine these pain points with his service offering of “project management that incubates projects?” Reply to this email and I’ll pass along the message.
—Robert
PS. I’m sending 1200 high quality project leads a year to a private list of freelancers. I’ll be raising the price this Friday, wouldn’t you feel better signing up now? There’s zero-risk. Try it for a full month and if the leads aren’t up to snuff, get your money-back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing/2017/06/05/rewriting-a-headline.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing/2017/06/05/rewriting-a-headline.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Most lucrative email you can send in the next 5 minutes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The most lucrative email you can send in the next 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-simple-send-a-follow-up-email-to-all-your-past-clients&quot;&gt;It’s simple. Send a follow up email to ALL your past clients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might already be feeling some resistance to this idea, that’s good: this is the #1 most underutilized tactic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See because you’re always on the lookout for more work, you don’t realize the number one most likely place to get work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even successful freelancers don’t do this enough. Find all of your clients from the past 2-3 years (you can even go beyond this). To find these all of these clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;look at your bank account and sort by income&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to your stripe account and see who’s paid you&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look at paypal, or your email address for “invoice”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m betting you’ll find one or two clients you forgot existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll quickly have over 10+ people who you probably haven’t followed up with recently, that’s OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put them all on a list, a spreadsheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Send them a super simple, quick email:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey [first name], just wanted to follow up and see how your business is doing. Is there anything I can do to help grow your business? Give me a call if you need help :) Talk soon, [Your name] [Your Phone Number]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll be amazed how well this works. You’ll undoubtably hear back from a few of them with urgent projects. These are highly-qualified people who are 10x more likely to hire you - yet you forget about them because you’re always looking for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk about how to automate this in another lesson but this is how you create a recurring stream of clients coming to you, by simply sending a short email every 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By BUILDING on what you establish, not constantly throwing away your hard work sweat and tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a workshop customer I’ll remind you to follow-up with these clients every 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/tag/2017/06/05/most-lucrative-email-to-send.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/tag/2017/06/05/most-lucrative-email-to-send.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tag</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
