<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop - Get great clients sent to you everyday</title>
    <description>Get over 200+ hand selected freelance web consulting leads sent to your inbox every week</description>
    <link>http://letsworkshop.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://letsworkshop.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 13:40:35 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 13:40:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
=======
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 13:33:47 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 13:33:47 -0700</lastBuildDate>
=======
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 14:32:49 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 14:32:49 -0700</lastBuildDate>
>>>>>>> fb9067a9ffdafc1266d5f8137cc3d9f6d1d9dce4
>>>>>>> 61d47e9e851abbad988aae4309d77895716bc598
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>RFPs the smart way</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; With RFPs, in particular, there’s a high-risk of wasting time on thing that have no impact on results. This includes finding RFP’s, designing proposals, and following up by hand. Instead, automate your proposals and follow-ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;img-classemoji-titlehand-althand-srchttpsassetsgithubcomimagesiconsemojiunicode270bpng-height20-width20-alignabsmiddle-wait-are-rfps-even-worth-responding-to&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:hand:&quot; alt=&quot;:hand:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/270b.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Wait, are RFPs even worth responding to?&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ahh, the elusive RFP. Unless you have a lot of experience with them, they can be down-right intimidating. But even the top design agencies in the world reply to them. Take world-renowned designer, Mike Monteiro, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;book-recommendation-quote&quot;&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;book-recommendation&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://abookapart.com/products/design-is-a-job&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/designisajob.jpg&quot; style=&quot;box-shadow: 0px 0px 8px #AAA;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;cite&gt;Highly recommended for consultancies.&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;curly-quote&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/span&gt;There are many good organizations that have to go through an RFP process to hire anyone. And those are good jobs to go after. People who tell you they don’t go after RFPs and people who tell you they don’t have meetings are both lying to you.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;div class=&quot;by-line&quot;&gt;
			&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mikemonteiro.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;div&gt;
				Mike Monteiro&lt;br /&gt; 
				Co-founder, Mule Design
				&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Of course, it is better to get work &lt;a href=&quot;/referrals&quot;&gt;by referral&lt;/a&gt; BUT simply responding to 1-2 RFPs per week can mean millions of dollars in added revenue (over the course of a few years) for &lt;em&gt;not that much extra effort&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That makes RFPs a great opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;With the right approach, you can reduce the intimidation factor substantially.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This guide will show you how - and it will help you create a system that takes just a couple hours a week to manage.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In fact, if you follow the advice in the guide, I guarantee you’ll be able to reply to projects (with realistic budgets and great people at the helm) no matter how busy you are.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-make-rfps-suck-less&quot;&gt;How to make RFPs suck less&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;RFPs suck because they’re time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Often we think there’s no feedback involved, but the truth is we just don’t take advantage of that’s feedback available.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This means you’re left feeling like you just did a ton of work for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Failed proposals feel particularly pointless because after a few you start to wonder if you ever had a shot in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Are all of these carefully crafted proposals being sent to a black hole? Nobody got time for that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Yet, the truth is quite a different picture. Most RFP issuers I’ve interviewed received less than 30 proposals total.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That means if you do some simple math, your chances are &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’re &lt;strong&gt;just average&lt;/strong&gt; at sending proposals - and respond to one a week - you’re guaranteed to land a couple gigs every year.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;With the average budget size of 30-40k for an RFP, that’s not a bad ROI as long as responding to one RFP a week doesn’t make you hate your life.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So let’s talk about how to make the process way easier.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;know-what-a-great-rfp-looks-like&quot;&gt;1. Know what a great RFP looks like&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;How to identify a winnable, RFP. Over the years I’ve found thousands of RFPs. However, most of them I didn’t include to members of my service? I knew my members would have NO chance of winning most of them. Why? A couple reasons. To find the a quality RFP you have to look fro a few different traits.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;look-for-private-over-non-profit-over-government&quot;&gt;Look for private over non-profit over government&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Government RFPs are the first i look to remove. They’re some of the least likely leads I would apply to. There’s usually a large bearucratic process involved that can even span years. There’s all kinds of red tape involved.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;On the other hand. Non-profit rfps can be great. Just make sure they have an actual budget and aren’t expecting a free service or donation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Private company RFPs are the hardest to find, usually because companies like this typically only send them out to a handful of agencies. When I find these I put a premium on them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[Image of what a good RFP looks like vs Long one]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;look-for-rfps-written-by-humans&quot;&gt;Look for RFPs written by humans&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Another reason government RFPs suck is because they’re so long. In general short RFPs are going to be better because they’re not overly prescriptive. Look for RFPs you can understand quickly. This tip will serve you well throughout the project because it’s an indicator that clear thought and communication is a priority for the organization you’re pitching.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The problem with most RFPs is that they’re written by people who are as irritated that they have to write it as you are that you have to reply to it.
That’s also the key to handling an RFP. Find out who wrote it. Most come with a contact number in case you have questions. Call it. Make friends with the people who wrote it. They may have even heard of you. If so, you’re golden. Strike up a conversation with them and get as much detail as you can about the organization involved.&lt;br /&gt;
Mike Monteiro&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;make-sure-theyre-not-overly-prescriptive&quot;&gt;Make sure they’re not overly prescriptive&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The other problem with RFPs is that they can be overly prescriptive in nature. They can include specific solutions that may or may not be appropriate. This is usually an indication that the organization is freaked out about having to hire designers and is trying to maintain as much control as possible—to the point where they’re going into as much detail as possible and short-circuiting the entire design process. You may be able to help them through that.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;make-creating-proposals-a-snap-by-re-using-stuff-everyone-asks-for&quot;&gt;2. Make creating proposals a snap by re-using stuff everyone asks for&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The truth is most RFPs ask for the exact same 6-8 things.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;RFP specifications are so similar in fact, you can apply to 90% of them with almost an identical proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Instead of wasting time re-making a proposal from scratch, you can create a great proposal once that you re-use again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So what are the elements you should have ready to go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-elements-grid&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;

    &lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-save-hours-on-rfps-prep-these-elements&quot;&gt;How to save hours on RFPs: prep these elements&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Below is a list of the most most common specs you’ll be asked to provide, based on analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;http://app.letsworkshop.com/leads&quot;&gt;over 500 RFPs&lt;/a&gt;. Have these ready to go and you’ll save you a ton of time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:email:&quot; alt=&quot;:email:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2709.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Cover letter&lt;/h3&gt;
Introduce yourself in a friendly and concise way. Add something unique to the project you&#39;re applying to.
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:nail_care:&quot; alt=&quot;:nail_care:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f485.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Bio&lt;/h3&gt;
Share with clients who&#39;s behind the proposal. Have a bio ready to go that tells them why you&#39;re awesome.
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:telephone_receiver:&quot; alt=&quot;:telephone_receiver:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4de.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Contact Info&lt;/h3&gt;
Make it clear what the best way to contact you is. Ideally, include this info on every page (especially the last).
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:beers:&quot; alt=&quot;:beers:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f37b.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Team members&lt;/h3&gt;
Define roles for members on your team. Let the client know who else will be working on their project.
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:bar_chart:&quot; alt=&quot;:bar_chart:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4ca.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
What are you proposing? What&#39;s the benefit? You&#39;ll be surprised how often you can re-use &quot;custom&quot; solutions.
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:moneybag:&quot; alt=&quot;:moneybag:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4b0.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Price&lt;/h3&gt;
How much is it going to cost? Include options. Sometimes you will need to stay within a  range set in the RFP.
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;element&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:raising_hand:&quot; alt=&quot;:raising_hand:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f64b.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
Most RFPs have a Q+A process baked in. Always have a couple of questions ready to go for any  project.
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot;&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:eyes:&quot; alt=&quot;:eyes:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f440.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;Want to see an example? Download now&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:sparkles:&quot; alt=&quot;:sparkles:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2728.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;shave-hours-off-the-process-by-using-a-proposal-app&quot;&gt;3. Shave hours off the process by using a proposal app&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Once you have these elements in place, you will still spend an outrageous amount of time designing your proposals. Surprisingly, this activity has almost no effect on the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s why I recommend that instead you drop these common elements into proposal software and be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This will make it stupid easy to drag and drop elements to create 100% customer proposals in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There’s a few options, so I’ve taken the time to highlight a few of my favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;here-are-my-favorite-proposal-apps&quot;&gt;Here are my favorite proposal apps:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-proposal-apps&quot;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;recommendation bidsketch&quot;&gt;
		&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot;&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M23.334 11.96c-.713-.726-.872-1.829-.393-2.727.342-.64.366-1.401.064-2.062-.301-.66-.893-1.142-1.601-1.302-.991-.225-1.722-1.067-1.803-2.081-.059-.723-.451-1.378-1.062-1.77-.609-.393-1.367-.478-2.05-.229-.956.347-2.026.032-2.642-.776-.44-.576-1.124-.915-1.85-.915-.725 0-1.409.339-1.849.915-.613.809-1.683 1.124-2.639.777-.682-.248-1.44-.163-2.05.229-.61.392-1.003 1.047-1.061 1.77-.082 1.014-.812 1.857-1.803 2.081-.708.16-1.3.642-1.601 1.302s-.277 1.422.065 2.061c.479.897.32 2.001-.392 2.727-.509.517-.747 1.242-.644 1.96s.536 1.347 1.17 1.7c.888.495 1.352 1.51 1.144 2.505-.147.71.044 1.448.519 1.996.476.549 1.18.844 1.902.798 1.016-.063 1.953.54 2.317 1.489.259.678.82 1.195 1.517 1.399.695.204 1.447.072 2.031-.357.819-.603 1.936-.603 2.754 0 .584.43 1.336.562 2.031.357.697-.204 1.258-.722 1.518-1.399.363-.949 1.301-1.553 2.316-1.489.724.046 1.427-.249 1.902-.798.475-.548.667-1.286.519-1.996-.207-.995.256-2.01 1.145-2.505.633-.354 1.065-.982 1.169-1.7s-.135-1.443-.643-1.96zm-12.584 5.43l-4.5-4.364 1.857-1.857 2.643 2.506 5.643-5.784 1.857 1.857-7.5 7.642z&quot; /&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;My top recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bidsketch.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 250px; width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Bidsketch is the only proposal software I&#39;ve used extensively because it does everything I need. It creates proposals, stores templates, and allows you to require a signature.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;What makes Bidsketch particularly great for RFPs is that they emphasize selling benefits and re-using elements of past proposals. Strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bidsketch.com&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Starts at $29/mo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p style=&quot;margin-top:0;color: #6d6e60;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:heart:&quot; alt=&quot;:heart:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2764.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; &lt;small&gt;Not an affiliate link.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;recommendation cushion&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cushion.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100px; width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another option:&lt;/strong&gt; I recently came across an app called Cushion which looks great, especially if you need to track time and visualize your schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cushionapp.com&quot;&gt;Starts at $5/month&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;recommendation remarq&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/remarq.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 50px; width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For markdown lovers:&lt;/strong&gt; Remarq is also a solid option. I&#39;ve heard great things from numerous consultants about using Remarq.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.remarq.io&quot;&gt;Starts at $19/month&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center; grid-column: span 2; font-size: 80%; color: #666; padding: 1em 0;&quot;&gt;
		Am I missing an awesome proposal app? &lt;a href=&quot;MAILTO:robert@letworkshop.com&quot;&gt;Let me know&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this guide, I’ll be using Bidsketch.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Note: above all, it’s just important that you use SOMETHING to create proposals. Don’t waste time in InDesign or Keynote. It’s not worth it.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;create-a-follow-up-sequence-that-sends-automatically&quot;&gt;4. Create a follow up sequence that sends automatically&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Now that you can create proposals in a snap, it’s important to make the most of then.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You do that by communicating.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Now, yes, following up on your proposals, touching base with people you’re courting, , and asking great questions can get extremely cumbersome.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;For a lot of agencies this proves too much.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;They forget to reply to an email, they never follow-up, and opportunities end up falling through the cracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;short-quote&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 900px; text-align: center; color: #444; margin: 2em auto;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 150%;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;curly-quote&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/span&gt;In the confrontation between the rock and the stream, the stream always wins. So follow-up.
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;color: #666; margin: 1em 0 0;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/buddha.png&quot; style=&quot;vertical-align: -9px; margin-right: .5em; width: 30px; border-radius: 30px;&quot; /&gt; Buddha
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ok I added that last part. But what the big guy was trying to say is that taking action beats sitting still.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When it comes to RFP’s, value consistency over tenacity.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s why the firms who do the best with RFP’s are the ones who have a system in place for replying to them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(And I’ve watched first-hand as these firms made $100k+ from my RFP-finding service.)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To do this, they either hire someone like a VA who’s sole job is sending out these proposals, or they develop a process that works automatically in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I’m going to walk you through how I’d set this sort of system up now.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;… but remember, you’re just trying to send one proposal per week - that’s it. Look at it as a numbers game and don’t sweat it when your don’t hear back. Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rfp-follow-up-campaign&quot;&gt;The RFP follow-up campaign&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The goal of this email campaign is to open up a dialogue with the people who are running the RFP process. You’re not looking to win the project with these emails - in fact - you’re not even looking to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Instead you’re simply looking to get a reply from the person you’ll be sending a proposal to. Simply getting a response and KNOWING that a real-life breathing person is behind the computer screen is the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s why we’ll be sending a simple 4-email outreach campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideally, this campaign will start 2 weeks before the RFP deadline:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;rfp-email-campaign-outline&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;when&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:speech_balloon:&quot; alt=&quot;:speech_balloon:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4ac.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; First email
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;what&quot;&gt;
		Say hello and ask a simple question.
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;when&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:raising_hand:&quot; alt=&quot;:raising_hand:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f64b.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; 5 days later
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;what&quot;&gt;
		If no response, follow up on your question.
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;when&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:sleeping:&quot; alt=&quot;:sleeping:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f634.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; 4 days later
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;what&quot;&gt;
		If no response, follow up again.
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;when&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:scissors:&quot; alt=&quot;:scissors:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2702.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; 3 days later
	&lt;/div&gt; 
	&lt;div class=&quot;what&quot;&gt;
		If still no response, close the loop.
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Each one of these emails will come before the proposal deadline that way you know if you should spend time crafting a proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The key is to ask an extremely simple question so that you know there’s a real person reading the replies.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s all you want. A fighting chance.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So what should these emails say? You’ll be amazed at how simple they can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;inline-video-bonus&quot; style=&quot;margin: 1em 0; display: grid; grid-template-columns: 2fr 5fr; font-size: 80%; grid-gap: 2rem; border-top: 1px solid #eee; border-bottom: 1px solid #eee; padding: 1em 0;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/video-placeholder.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin: 1em auto; display: inline-block; max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div&gt;
      &lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: .5em 0 0; font-size: 110%;&quot;&gt;Screencast: Watch me set up this campaign&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It’s simple to create an automatic outreach campaign that you use to respond to RFPs. Watch me setup the campaign I’m outlining below and save hours of trial and error. &lt;strong&gt;Watch the bonus video:&lt;/strong&gt; Bluetick or Quickmail (coming soon)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;writing-your-emails&quot;&gt;Writing your emails&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Remember the questions we prepared earlier in this guide? You’re going to pick one of them to use as a conversation starter.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Pick the one that’s easiest to answer. Ideally, clients should be able to respond to it with a simple “yes.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;your-opening-email&quot;&gt;Your Opening Email&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;rfp-email-example&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-number&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;1&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-message&quot;&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Subject:&lt;/strong&gt; great project
		
		&lt;hr style=&quot;margin: .5em 0;&quot; /&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;John&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Your RFP looks great.&lt;/p&gt; 
		
		&lt;p&gt;You clearly care about the outcome of the project - so I wanted to check-in and ask &lt;span class=&quot;insert-question-here&quot;&gt;question&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;Thanks&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The key here is to ask an extremely simple question. How simple? You want even the busiest person in the world to be able to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;example-good-bad&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Example&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;div class=&quot;good&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:thumbsup:&quot; alt=&quot;:thumbsup:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f44d.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;good-question&quot;&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Are you the right person to talk to about this project?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good:&lt;/strong&gt; All I have to say is: yes!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;bad&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:x:&quot; alt=&quot;:x:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/274c.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;div class=&quot;bad-question&quot;&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Do you think my agency is a fit for your project?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad:&lt;/strong&gt; I&#39;m not sure how to answer this.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;download&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:sparkles:&quot; alt=&quot;:sparkles:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2728.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt; For more examples of questions that are easy to respond to, &lt;a href=&quot;/ctas&quot;&gt;check out my cta swipe file&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Now, onto the second and third emails.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;your-follow-ups&quot;&gt;Your Follow-ups&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;rfp-email-example&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-number&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;2&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-message&quot;&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Subject:&lt;/strong&gt; RE: great project
		
		&lt;hr style=&quot;margin: .5em 0;&quot; /&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;Following up incase you missed my question.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;rfp-email-example&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-number&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;3&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-message&quot;&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Subject:&lt;/strong&gt; RE: great project
		
		&lt;hr style=&quot;margin: .5em 0;&quot; /&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m following up to see if you&#39;re still looking for proposals. If so, I&#39;d love to see how we can work together. &lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Look, I know these emails look too simple.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But don’t be afraid, you’re simply following up on an email you sent. You’re not going to bug the person you’re emailing, they’re busy, they might not have time to get back to you at the exact moment you emailed them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So a couple simple follow-up emails is all you need.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;your-loop-closer&quot;&gt;Your Loop Closer&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;rfp-email-example&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-number&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;step&quot;&gt;4&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;email-message&quot;&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Subject:&lt;/strong&gt; RE: great project
		
		&lt;hr style=&quot;margin: .5em 0;&quot; /&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Since I have not heard from you on this, I have to assume your priorities have changed.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This email is dubbed &lt;a href=&quot;http://themagicemail.com&quot;&gt;The Magic Email&lt;/a&gt; because it works so well at getting a client who has ignored you to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s considerate because you’re taking the initiative to close the loop on the conversation that never started.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is how professionals close the loop.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;rules-if-a-client-responds-to-one-of-these-emails&quot;&gt;2 rules: If a client responds to one of these emails…&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;emoji-list&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;div class=&quot;emoji-list-row&quot;&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:love_letter:&quot; alt=&quot;:love_letter:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f48c.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;div&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Their organization should receive a proposal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The entire goal of this sequence is to get a dialogue started with the people who issued these RFPs. If a client responds to one of these emails and answers your question - you’re in business.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;emoji-list-row&quot;&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:see_no_evil:&quot; alt=&quot;:see_no_evil:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f648.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;div&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They should no longer receive subsequent follow-up emails.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That’s why it’s important to automate this campaign using software like &lt;a href=&quot;http://bluetick.io&quot;&gt;Bluetick.io&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://quickmail.io&quot;&gt;Quickmail.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;short-quote&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 900px; text-align: center; color: #444; margin: 2em auto;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 120%;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;curly-quote&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/span&gt;Any RFP I’m interested in, I ask them one simple question. If they can answer it directly, I’ll move forward. If not, I move on.
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;color: #666; margin: 1em 0 0;&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kurt.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;vertical-align: -9px; margin-right: .5em; width: 30px; border-radius: 30px;&quot; /&gt; Kurt Elster, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ethercycle.com&quot;&gt;Ethercycle&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;
  &lt;hr /&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;a-few-more-ways-to-dramatically-improve-your-chances&quot;&gt;A few more ways to dramatically improve your chances…&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;emoji-list&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;div class=&quot;emoji-list-row&quot;&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:question:&quot; alt=&quot;:question:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/2753.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;div&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the Q+A process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Q+A process is one of the most underrated portions of the RFP process. Most consultants overlook it, but it’s the best way to make inroads with the person you’re contacting.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;emoji-list-row&quot;&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:school_satchel:&quot; alt=&quot;:school_satchel:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f392.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;div&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Inside your proposal you should have a few different packages that clients can choose from. This is something I learned in &lt;a href=&quot;http://freepricingcourse.com/?ref=workshop&quot;&gt;Brennan Dunn’s free pricing course&lt;/a&gt;. Strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;emoji-list-row&quot;&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;emoji&quot; title=&quot;:phone:&quot; alt=&quot;:phone:&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.github.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/260e.png&quot; height=&quot;20&quot; width=&quot;20&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
&lt;div&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call them&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
One of the best ways to stand out is to give prospects a ring. One of the benefits of RFPs is that they almost always include a phone number. A simple 5-minute phone call introducing yourself can be enough to separate you from the pack. Pro-tip pick up the phone&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;If an RFP starts dictating button colors, pick up the phone. It’s a cry for help and your opportunity to create mutual understanding. Speaking directly to a designer may be what they need, much more than getting 325 replies to a badly-formed RFP. Remember, not all organizations who send out formal documents have to.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;create-your-own-luck-on-purpose&quot;&gt;Create your own luck… on purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With RFPs there’s always going to be some luck involved. However, you can also create the opportunity for luck to strike by putting yourself in the right position. Be consistent. Send 50-100 RFPs over the course of a year. Followup consistently. Suddenly, you’ll find that you get a lot luckier.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

  &lt;h1 id=&quot;now-that-youre-an-rfp-master-where-the-heck-do-you-find-rfps&quot;&gt;Now that you’re an RFP master… where the heck do you find RFPs?&lt;/h1&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So far we’ve covered how to make it dead simple to reply to RFPs and give yourself the best possible chance at finding them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The last part of this guide will be dedicated to finding them and reducing the amount of time this takes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why? Because it can actually be really time consuming to find RFPs. The problem is they’re usually spread around the web.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Companies post them on their website and share them with a few people they know. That can make them difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;they-key-is-to-make-rfps-come-to-you&quot;&gt;They key is to make RFPs come to you…&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Luckily there’s a few websites that help. Below I’ve compiled the best sources for RFPs I’ve found over years of testing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Instead of chasing down RFPs across thousands of websites, you can monitor a few sites. Let’s start with my service though. Here’s some recent RFPs I’ve found and sent to members of this website:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h1 id=&quot;siren-right-here-rfps-now-hiring&quot;&gt;:siren: Right here! RFPs now hiring…&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-rss&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-rss-row&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brunson.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
			RFPs the smart way
		    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;June 10&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-rss-row&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brunson.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
			RFPs the smart way
		    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;June 10&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-rss-row&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brunson.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
			RFPs the smart way
		    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;June 10&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-rss-row&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brunson.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
			RFPs the smart way
		    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;June 10&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-rss-row&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/brunson.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;
			RFPs the smart way
		    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;June 10&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;All of these RFPs are high-quality projects I found myself in the last few days. I send them to paying members of my service &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h3 id=&quot;prefer-to-find-rfps-yourself-heres-where-and-how&quot;&gt;Prefer to find RFPs yourself? Here’s where and how…&lt;/h3&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/google-logo.svg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; max-width: 200px; margin-top: 2em;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Google is actually a great source for RFPs because what you want is to search across thousands of independent websites.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The trick is you want to type &lt;span class=&quot;include-this&quot;&gt;type:pdf&lt;/span&gt; in your search. That way you get PDFs of the RFPs you’re looking for, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/google-type-pdf-tutorial.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: 1px solid #eee; border-radius: 5px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Next you’re going to want to change your search results to show you stuff created in the last week. Google doesn’t do this automatically so it will save you some time not finding and getting excited about an RFP from last year.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/google-past-week.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: 1px solid #eee; border-radius: 5px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Overall as a source of leads Google ranks pretty high among the services I’ve tried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-source-scorecard&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;
		Scorecard
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;rating&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;8.5&lt;/span&gt;
		Score
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;volume&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;4-8/mo&lt;/span&gt;
		RFP Volume 
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;cost&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/span&gt;
		Price
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;1 hour&lt;/span&gt;
		Time commitment
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=type:pdf+website+design+rfp&amp;amp;num=50&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;source=lnt&amp;amp;tbs=qdr:w&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjyofzqt7TUAhVE6GMKHcLwAtAQpwUIIA&amp;amp;biw=1151&amp;amp;bih=631&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; style=&quot;margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;Use google now&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

  &lt;h1 id=&quot;rfpdbcom&quot;&gt;RFPdb.com&lt;/h1&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Another great source of RFPs is RFPdb. The site is credit-based so you pay for a minimum of 10 credits and you can access RFPs (2 credits each).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You can also share RFPs on the site to get access to more credits. Every RFP has a free (censored) blurb about the project.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rfpdb.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: 1px solid #eee; border-radius: 5px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Usually, you can gain enough from this blurb to tell whether it’s relevant to you or not. That way you don’t waste credits on an RFP you don’t care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;rfp-source-scorecard&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;header&quot;&gt;
		Scorecard
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;rating&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;8.5&lt;/span&gt;
		Score
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;volume&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;8-12/mo&lt;/span&gt;
		RFP Volume 
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;cost&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;$10/week&lt;/span&gt;
		Price
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;time&quot;&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;score&quot;&gt;30 mins&lt;/span&gt;
		Time commitment
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;reading wrap&quot;&gt;

  &lt;center&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://rfpdb.com&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; style=&quot;margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;Use RFPdb now&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;rfpalooza&quot;&gt;RFPalooza&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scorcard:&lt;/strong&gt;
No. of quality leads per month: 6-8
Time commitment: 30 minutes
Price: About $10 per week 
Rating: &lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h2 id=&quot;findrfp&quot;&gt;FindRFP&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Quality leads per week: 1-2 a week&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Workshop
Another way to get RFPs is through my lead service. This is my lead service. I basically do the leg work of finding RFPs off these other sites for you and just send you the good stuff off these other sites.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Quality leads per week: 2-3 a week&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;RFPs are an interesting animal. From my experience, most of the marketing folks involved with sending an RFP out for bid don’t even want to do it… they have to. I have a rather pleasant ongoing contract with a large state organization in PA, and they were smart enough to use their 1-year extension option with my contract to avoid having to send this out for bid yearly. Every other year, however, they are required by the state auditor general to do this RFP crap… just like every other state funded organization in PA. They don’t have to choose by price, and in the end they get to make the final call so long as it fit’s their budget plan. As Kurt Elster said, the RFPs are written with someone particular in mind for the job (me). It’s nice to be on the inside of that situation, but they are difficult to respond to for folks on the outside looking in. Sometimes you just get lucky! For me, when it comes to RFPs, I always weigh the value of the project against the time and hassle involved. If it’s an ongoing contract, I usually give it a little more consideration. I’m a big fan of guaranteed income. Moral of the story is that hatred for the RFP is mutual in a lot of instances. Shared by Workshop member Corey Tiani&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;!--





## Some RFPs you can reply to right now
[RSS feed]

--&gt;

  &lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;brought-to-you-by&quot; style=&quot;display:grid; grid-template-columns: 1fr 3fr;	grid-gap: 2rem; max-width: 1000px; margin: 1em auto;padding: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/workshop-logo.svg&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 150px; width: 100%; display: block; margin: 2em auto;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;

    &lt;h3 id=&quot;this-guide-is-brought-to-you-by-my-service-workshop&quot;&gt;This guide is brought to you by my service Workshop&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Members of my service get a head start on this entire process because I go out and find RFPs for them that are qualified, easy to read, and have all the good stuff highlighted for them. You should apply today.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robertwilliams.typeform.com/to/XVOd5o&quot; class=&quot;button&quot;&gt;Apply now • $199&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/rfps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/rfps/</guid>
        
        
        <category>job_boards</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When to follow-up</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;x5-technique&quot;&gt;5X5 technique&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since in another lesson we established that the person who actually wins the client isn’t the one who does the most prep-work or who sends the best email or at the first email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What really is the most important thing is the timing. So how do you know the right time to follow up on an email? When should you send a follow up without being too pushy. The last thing you want to do is annoy the person you’re emailing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you walk that skinny line between emailing too soon, and emailing too late. After all you also don’t want to hurt your chances by following up after the client has already made a decision or forgotten about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Workshop we’ve had the unique privilege of studying thousands of freelancer and agency emails to clients so we’ve been able to observe what works and what doesn’t. We’ve developed the perfect follow-up system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 days. That’s how long you should wait in between followups. 5 days is the perfect number because it’s not so soon that the client feels rushed but it’s also not so long that you fall behind someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a client is interested in hiring someone and it’s a decent project, 5 days is how long it takes to go from “omgosh I don’t know who to pick” to “ok I’m ready to pick someone”. That’s when you want to send your follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also gives them time to breathe. I’m not kidding when I say that some client service firms like to follow-up the SAME DAY they send an email. Not only is this WAY to fast. It’s rude. Why are you assuming that every person checks  their email multiple times a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give me a break. Let me go a day or two or three before I respond to you. Don’t try to rush me because all that does is make me want to reply to you even less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the spectrum is people who follow up too late. They wait for weeks before they send a followup. This is inconsiderate too. I need help now. Maybe your email fell behind and I didn’t have  a chance to respond… two weeks later you’ve missed the boat. I’ve moved on. I might’ve picked someone else or things have changed. You weren’t there to help guide that process so now you’ve lost the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5-7 days is the optimal time to followup. No shorter, no later. Don’t succumb to the temptation that most fall into, you’re playing the long game. You’re not in the game of creating pressure tactics or fumbling along clumsily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next question is how many times do you follow-up? Now that you know that 5 days between your follow ups is the optimal amount of time - the next question becomes how many times becomes too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s two different answers. One is for people who you email cold and don’t get a positive response. The answer here is you should only followup a maximum of 4-5 times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason is that if they’ve never shown interest then they’re probably not interested. That’s a long enough span to safely assume, if they can’t get back to you that you’ve probably struck out this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means follow up with them a few months down the line, but for now its safe to assume they’ve gone silent for long enough and you should move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you make this clear though. On your final email send the magic email. Close the loop with your lead by saying “Since I haven’t heard from you on this I have to assume you’re not interested” leave it at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most effective ways of getting a response. Once you send this email don’t followup again for at least 4 months, if ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the other type of person you follow up with is someone who HAS shown interest at some point. Maybe they were interested in your service or you even got into talks about their specific project and did some consultation or discovery calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When suddenly they stop responding. With these people it’s OK to followup forever. The thing is people get busy. As a client service business it’s your job to make sure they don’t forget about you. It’s YOUR job to make sure you look out for them and keep yourself and the project top of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this your responsibility. Because your service is going to improve their business. Your service is going to create a net-positive ROI for them. They’ve already established they’re interested. They’re a busy business owner. They’re the person who stands to benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To look out for their best interest means to make sure they have the options available to them and not let them do anything less than the most they can accomplish. You are providing value before you ever start working by following up on a project that is going to create even more value for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So once a client expresses interest followup forever. Keep following up every 5-7 days until you get a hard no from them. There are countless stories from sales teams who followup for months on end without hearing back. They just keep following up until eventually the busy business owner replies and says something like “hey thanks for being so persistent I was out of town but this is something I really need to do”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know who’s awesome in that situation? You. Because you followed up. So now we’ve covered how long you should wait to follow up, and exactly how many times you should follow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magic of the followup happens when you begin to automate this process (that’s something we’re going to cover next).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But remember there’s value in a followup that comes at the right time. It’s all about timing. Don’t followup too soon - but make sure you follow up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-when-to-followup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-when-to-followup.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outreach campaigns</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably the least appealing part about using outreach to find clients is the idea that you’ll be chasing work from clients. Think about it, if you contact clients you’re instantly put in the lower position. It’s you who needs something from them. (And that’s very true). But there is a way to change that dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outreach should be about delivering value, establishing trust, and alerting qualified prospects about a possible fit. That’s it. Selling should be left for later. You can’t win a client in your outreach campaign. That has to happen at a later point. Why? Because of timing. Timing plays the biggest role of any in winning clients.  We’ll spend a whole lesson on Timing coming up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while you’re delivering value, establishing trust, and alerting qualified prospects about the potential of a great fit. You need to nudging them. Let me explain. As you first contact someone, there are indirect ways you can point them to you as a the obvious choice for their project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use your email signature to point prospects to an email course or your project inquiry form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can link to resources like guides or plugins you’ve created for clients in similar situations to them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can send them parts of blog posts you’ve written.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And yes, you can and should send them a note mentioning you’re perfect for their project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is once they know about you, once you’ve established the trust, and your value. Once you have mentioned you’re interested in taking on their project. This is where it’s time to back off. I don’t mean by not following up. THE OPPOSITE. Continue to follow up. Just don’t try advancing the conversation without ONE thing happening first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prospect client HAS to establish that they want YOU to work on their project. Before they do that you’re not allowed to try “closing the sale” you’re not even allowed to put them on your calendar. This is how you go from using outreach to sell clients, to using outreach to create inbound leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re using outreach to attract instead of chase. Make every single lead hit a wall. That wall in your project inquiry form. To advance beyond the wall they simply MUST submit that form. They need to take the time to answer questions you need about their project. They need to take the time. They need to INVEST something into working with you BEFORE you can start discussing the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice again I said they need to INVEST something into you and your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve done the same. You’ve delivered them value. You’ve found a useful piece of advice for them or delivered some wisdom to them. Use the rule of reciprocity to make your outreach more effective. By delivering value to them not only are you establishing trust, you’re making them be in debt to you. They’re going to want to at least interview you for the project. At least let you bid on the project. However, you’ll quickly let them know that this isn’t possible without a few things from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making clients invest in working with you will not only make it more likely they actually choose you for the project, it will make them happier throughout the project. You’ll have a list of answers - in their own words that talk about exactly what they need from the project. You’ll be able to tune your messaging to the same frequency they use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of all you become the one who’s sought after. The power dynamic of the relationship changes. You’re no longer chasing them for work. You’ve given them value. You’ve given them resources. You’ve established trust. Now it’s their turn. Now you’re the one on top and they’re coming to you for something they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your time. A chance to be on your schedule. You’ve made it so that everything has to happen on your terms. The person who has to do the work to make this happen changes accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at this point they stop replying or you don’t fill out your project inquiry form, it means you haven’t delivered enough value, or established enough trust. Continue to follow up with them until you get a no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue to brainstorm ideas for how you can help (use the list of ideas we covered in lesson X). If they go cold it likely means their busy. Use your regular follow up sequence covered in module X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another idea is to offer a small part of your time, like a free consult or a couple ideas for how you can help. Dangle this carrot in front of them by saying you can deliver this only after they fill out your project inquiry form. It’s very likely you’ll have to do a call with them anyway at some point before the project, so it makes sense for you to use this as an incentive. There’s literally no limit to the amount of things you could use as an incentive to create incentive for them to fill out this project inquiry form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key here is to create enough desire in them … NOT to close the sale. That’s not what the goal is. It’s for them to want to have you in on the process. It’s for the to look at you as a trusted resource they can come back to. Again it’s not trying to close the sale completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s for later in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stuff-not-to-include-in-your-email-signature&quot;&gt;Stuff not to include in your email signature:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stuff-not-to-include-in-your-email-signature-to-clients&quot;&gt;Stuff not to include in your email signature to clients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Williams,
Williams Interactive, LLC,
No Nonsense Hosting &amp;amp;
Imagination Plus Hosting Services
Phone: (646) 202-1882 ext. 101
Fax: (646) 619-4621
www.nolaninteractive.com
www.nononsensehosting.com
www.imaginationplushosting.com
———————————————–
Schedule a call with me:
calendly.com/jnolan
———————————————–
Get important updates:
twitter.com/Nolan_WebBrands
———————————————–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	The outreach email campaign that will qualify leads 
⁃	You’ll want to contact at least 15 leads each month. 
⁃	This sounds pretty easy but there’s some high-level psychology involved if you want to do it effectively
⁃	You don’t want to ask for something off the bat (like a phone call)
⁃	You don’t want to rush the process
⁃	You don’t want to make the conversation about you or what you’ll get from it
⁃	Instead you want to make the email about the person you’re emailing
⁃	Ideally you’d like to deliver something of value with this email
⁃	Let’s take a look at a real life situation so we can break down the process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Taking your cold outreach email from GOOD to GREAT
⁃	Now the email we wrote in the last module is pretty good
⁃	It’s already better than 90% of what people will send. 
⁃	However, it’s not perfect, heres how we take it to the next level
⁃	Use a tool like Quickmail which automates followups and makes sure you follow up with 100% of leads
⁃	I can’t stress this enough if you only take one thing from this course it’s that following up with cold emails will 4x your response rate BY ITSELF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	Pouring leads into this cold outreach campaign
⁃	Once you have your cold email outreach campaign in place optimized and ready you don’t want to do the process of finding leads to pour in yourself. Atleast not forever.
⁃	I’m going to share with you the exact scripts I use with my VA’s to find leads.
⁃	This is years of training and seeing exactly what works for you
⁃	In the bonus for this module you’ll see my process document and a video tutorial for training a lead-finding VA
⁃	Places you can tell a VA to find you leads to drop in to your campaign:
⁃	Job Boards
⁃	Local Clients
⁃	Inc 5000
⁃	Yellow pages
⁃	Linkedin (check out Leadfuze)
⁃	Hiring someone to do this costs 300-600 a MONTH
⁃	The value of knowing that you have an outreach email going out that’s super effective is worth twice that price alone
⁃	I also offer a done for you service where I deliver 12-15 different types of frealcner and agency leads to you each weekday for $199 a month
⁃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	The second step outreach email that will push people to your contact form
⁃	So once this email starts generating replies it’s time to put them on a new campaign
⁃	I recommend that this campaign still be automated but push people to your contact form. 
⁃	We’ll talk about your contact form next, and what happens after that in future modules. schedule calls for you 
⁃	Once you have leads that are responding to your contact form questionnaire
⁃	You want to tell them:
⁃	Sounds great! 
⁃	Deliver even more value
⁃	Push them to fill out the contact form on your website, only this time call it a discovery form&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-outreach-campaigns.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-outreach-campaigns.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Non-US companies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How do you improve your chances as a firm outside the US looking to land clients? Here’s my tips for you on the way that I would approach companies in the US as an outside firm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to give you some very straight forward advice - others would sugar coat it but I’m not going to - I’m just going to tell you with no BS what you’re doing wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, here’s a few quick things that I would change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Never use “Greetings” just say “Hello” or use their first name. “Greetings” sounds like an alien bot and people will immediate think you are spam.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would shorten your name in gmail to just use Vlad Federov. Vlad is more common here and so western clients will be more familiar with it and more comfortable with you. Look, I know this is not fair or right, but it will probably get you better results.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You don’t want to say you do it all. This comes off extremely unprofessional. Instead you want to be world-class at one hyper-focused thing. In this scenario they’re looking for someone great at publishing and marketing. you need to focus your email on this specific need of theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t include quotes, unless they’re from the head of very well known companies - they won’t get read anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve never heard the expression “no underwater rocks”. I don’t think this is common. 
Your email is too long. You are coming off pushy, and like you are rushing to the sale when you have not established a need yet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Name
When you send off an email the recipient is only going to have 2 ways to get information about you to decide if htey shoudl open the meail. Your subject line and your name. My recommendation is to make your name something that is recognizable. This might seem weird so if you re uncomfortable with it i understand, but I’m just here to give you tips that will help improve your response and open rate. So, for example, you could go by Mat Ross. A common nickname here in the US is Mat so people are used to seeing that name. That’s a name that wouldn’t raise suspicision on my end of anythign and you jsut seem normal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t bring up that you’re a foreign company pre-maturely
Think of this like dating. When you’re courting someone you don’t bring up your faults (or something that you’re not sure they will perceive as a fault) atleast not until you’ve established a connection. You want to put your best foot forward, you don’t want to lie or keep the information frmo them especially if they ask. But you also don’t want to bring it up in the first email when there is no need. (That said, of course you want to tell them at some point. My recommendation is you do this on a call.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use the phrase “with past clients…”
If a client brings up the fact that you’re outside of the country as a concenr, one of the best ways to ease their concern is to use the phrase “with past clients in your timezone,  we found that being available and leaving an overlap of 3 hours every workday was actually more than enough. In fact, in a lot of ways it was actually better for them because they got to wake up to fresh work and it let them be more productive.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make english a priority
If you send me your emails I can almost gaurantee that I will be able to find some errors in your grammar. Its simply difficult to write perfect American english unless you’re completely native to the US.It’s also an easy way for companies to rationalize not responding to your email. Your english needs to be spotless at the beginning of the courtin gprocess. A lot of startups and firms in the us willl be able to spot weird colloquiialisms that don’t trasnalte from a mile away. This is one of the most common errors i asee frmo non-us based companies when pitching. You need to make sure there are not only no errors in grammmar but also no wierd phrases and other things. That make you seem out of place in thier inbox . I consider hiring someone to read this. And send emails on your behald. Bonuse points inf they’re in the usa.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t pitch yourself as a cheaper option
Even if you are infact cheaper you don’t want to sell pbased on a lower price. Instead you want to offer more better services. That is more incentivizing to people to know they can get more done than they can dsave a few bvucks. This will attract bad clients who just want the lowest price anyway. Not the type of clients you’er looking for. This also comes off as kind of scammy on your end like you’re desperate and you’ll say anything you need to make the sale.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is: how do you improve your chances as an outside firm looking to land clients inside the US?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I would do that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: I’m going to give you some very straight forward advice - I’m not going to sugar coat anything as I wouldn’t want someone to BS me either. I would just want someone to give it to me straight. All advice is solely with your success in mind, you don’t need to heed all of it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO think about your name - 
When someone receives an email from you there are only 2 bits of information to help them decide to open the email. One is your subject line, the other is your name. My recommendation is to use the native version of your name possible. This isn’t always possible, but to give you a couple examples, if your name is Vladislav I’d use Vlad. If your name is Mateo I’d use Matt. This might seem weird and it’s totally ok to not be comfortable with this approach, but I honestly think it would help improve your response / open rate. If people are used to seeing your name and comfortable with it, it’s one less thing they can discount you on. This isn’t about deceiving but instead putting your best foot forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO make English a priority
The fact is almost everyone makes errors in their emails. I do, you do. We all do. However, because you’re outside the US, your grammar is put under a microscope. A client who knows you’re from outside the US will worry about communication issues more than with a local company. It’s unfair but it’s the truth. You can ignore this fact, or you can prepare for it. Your english needs to be almost perfect at the beginning of the courting process. Make sure all of your emails make sense or a startup will be able to spot the weirdness from a mile away. This is one of the most common errors I see from non-us companies when pitching - and I know for a fact that it kills your response rate. You don’t want to use weird phrases that seem out of place. I would consider hiring someone to write/read the emails that is in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of a english mistake commonly made among non-US companies:
Using the salutation “Greetings” to start your email. Never use this phrase. Instead just say “Hello” or use their first name. “Greetings” sounds like an alien bot and people will immediate think you are spam. However, I’ve seen many foreign companies start their emails this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DON’T bring up that you’re a foreign company pre-maturely - 
This is another thing I see companies doing that shoots themselves in the foot. Think of it like dating. When you’re courting someone you don’t bring up your faults or things that can be perceived as a fault prematurely, instead you wait until you’ve established a connection and reveal more of yourself with team. Don’t get me wrong, you don’t want to hide the fact that you’re a foreign company  (that’s impossible anyway) but you also don’t want to create a roadblock by mentioning it for no reason. Again, you want to put your best foot forward, so my recommendation is the best time to let them know you’re outside the US is during your first call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DO use the phrase “with past clients in your timezone…”
If a client says that your company being outside the US is a concern, one of the best ways I’ve seen to ease this is to use past US clients as an example of the arrangement working well. For example instead of saying something like “don’t worry we can take care of your needs” you can say something like: “with past clients in your timezone, we found that giving a 3 hour overlap on weekdays was more than enough. In fact, in some ways it was actually better for them because they got to wake up to fresh work, something that let them be more productive and wouldn’t have been possible with a US based company.” Look for ways to pitch your uniqueness as an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DON’T pitch yourself as a cheaper option
Even if you are infact cheaper you don’t want your only selling point to be a lower price. This will make the client value you less. Instead of talking about your cheaper price, talk about more better services you offer. That is more intriguing to the type of clients you want. Instead of attracting bad clients who just want the lowest price, this will attract clients looking to get a lot done. Touting a lower price also comes off as kind of scammy on your end and can give a smell of desperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DON’T say you do it all.
Another common one among foreign companies. This comes off unprofessional. Instead of being able to handle everything, you want to be world-class at one hyper-focused thing.Focus your email on the specific need of theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-non-us-companies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-non-us-companies.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to write clearly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot;&gt;Clear writing&lt;/a&gt; is one of the biggest business advantages I can think of. By just making things easy to understand you’ll win more clients, more friends, and create better work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, confusing writing is very common. Organizing your thoughts and getting ideas across can be hard. Software never really helped, either. It usually just got in my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I toughed it out for a while. I’d write in Draft or a text editor, but organizing always became a mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I came across an old article by Edward T. Thompson for the International Paper Company. This article, How to Write Clearly, helped me more than any software I’ve come across. It’s how I wrote my new book &lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot;&gt;Emails That Win You Clients&lt;/a&gt; (now available for pre-order).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://knowingwhattosay.com/assets/downloads/writing-clearly.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://knowingwhattosay.com/assets/images/clear-writing.png&quot; alt=&quot;How To Write Clearly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basis of the technique is this: you write each point you want to make on an index card. This creates piles of index cards you can then set out and organize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It allowed me to group my writing into chapters and sections. Each card had a point I wanted to make, each stack of cards was a chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://knowingwhattosay.com/assets/images/etw-index-cards.png&quot; alt=&quot;Emails That Win index on my floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result is an extremely clear and focused book. It made it easy to make sure all the points I made built on each other. It all happens right in front of you in real-time so you can really focus on the order you want to say things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That makes your writing very logical and easy to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clear writing is a sign of clear thinking. – Jason Fried&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d recommend you read the article and practice the technique if you are a designer, marketer, or developer. It can really help with writing books, blog posts, emails, sales copy and virtually every type of marketing you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I showed it to a few of my friends in a mastermind chat, they started using it for picking features in app development and even planning and building client websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further reading on the topic and useful related articles and resources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/downloads/writing-clearly.pdf&quot;&gt;How to Write Clearly by Edward T. Thompson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot;&gt;Emails That Win You Clients&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/020530902X/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=020530902X&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=workshop0a2-20&amp;amp;linkId=MVGVTGFX6AXJSI7F&quot;&gt;Elements of Writing Style by William Strunk Jr.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-how-to-write-clearly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-how-to-write-clearly.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great CTAs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I collect great cold email calls to actions here when I come across them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some of the best call to actions I’ve ever read. They all made me reply when I read them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;cta-swipe&quot;&gt;
Robert&lt;br /&gt;

{ Insert crisp body email here that sets me up for the ask. } &lt;br /&gt;


	
	Is a conversation timely?
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Are you the right person to speak to about the project?
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Can I send over some ideas I have for the project?
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	I’d like to send you a few followup questions I had about the project - is that ok?
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Send me a thumbs up and I’ll send you more info.
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Feel free to respond and I’ll send you info
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Send me a yes and I’ll send more info
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Are you the right person? If not, who is?
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Cool? Is it ok if I tell you more?
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	Please reply to this email if I can send you some more info.
	&lt;hr /&gt;


	
	If you are the appropriate person to speak with, what does your calendar look like? If not, who do you recommend I talk to?
	&lt;hr /&gt;



&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last updated: June 5th, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-great-ctas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-great-ctas.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Establishing trust</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you know you need to build trust with potential clients before you ask for the sale. How can you do that? It seems like a really hard thing to do. To take someone from stranger to trusted confidant…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… All over email?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well no, you’re not really going to build that relationship over email. It just is going to start over email. We covered how to over deliver on value in the last module. Now we’re going to talk about building trust in this one. Building trust is a bit simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You build trust by first being honest with yourself. You need to not be afraid to give your honest feedback no matter what. Even if it means losing the client. If you don’t think you can help someone you shouldn’t bring them on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t think they need your services, you shouldn’t bring them on. The same can be said for your work. If you don’t think making a certain change in your work is really the best move than don’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, pick and choose your battles of course, but really if you’re not absolutely 100% behind a move, it’s your duty to let the client know. After all they’re paying you to give them your expert opinion. That’s the only reason they came to you. Don’t break that trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you take this approach and turn it to potential clients? Apply the same principles. Give your honest take. If that means saying no to a client’s project because you don’t think you can help, so be it. Sure you might lose out on a short-term revenue bump but you’ll also gain a whole lot of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One trick for this is to draw attention to your flaws. Now this seems counter-intuitive but place yourself in a buyers mind. For example, if you were buying an old chair from a antique mid-century modern dealer, and it was going to cost a pretty penny. Let’s say you noticed a small scratch on the inside of the chair. Would you trust a dealer who called attention to this scratch and made sure you know about it BEFORE you bought it? Or would you trust a dealer who quickly brushed over it and tried to make sure you didn’t see it with the angles he showed you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the difference between building trust and trying to sell. Take this approach when you talk to potential clients. Make sure what you’re recommending is in their best interest. Never do or sell something just for the money. It has to be about more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few more ways you can establish trust. Are through showing yourself to your clients. Show your work using case studies. Show what other clients have said with testimonials. Videos and podcasts are really great for building trust because the clients gets to see you and hear you. You always trust people who you know more intimately. Video and audio are a great way to up your level of intimacy quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now combine both of these to create something extremely trust building. Can you do a case study about a time you screwed up? If so that’s actually more powerful than a case study where everything went perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you record yourself talking about something you did wrong early in your career to make sure your prospects don’t make the same mistake?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sorts of ideas will not only help you estblaihs trust, it will give your clients an idea of your process. It demonstrates problem solving and the ability to make the best even when things go bad or aren’t perfect. That’s what a client really care about. Who can’t be awesome when everything goes perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A client wants someone who isn’t going to dip out of their project as soon as something goes wrong. That’s what’s going to build trust for them. Future clients need to envision themselves in it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-establishing-trust.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-establishing-trust.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emails that win</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-write-crisp-compelling-emails-that-land-you-more-work-in-less-time&quot;&gt;How to write crisp, compelling emails that land you more work in less time.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to spend big chunks of your day writing emails. Yet I’m willing to bet that you haven’t thought about improving this important skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me guess. You’ve sent emails to the following people without ever receiving replies: potential clients, people you admire and hoped to befriend, and colleagues or customers you wanted to support or serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they had responded to your emails, it would have meant:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The chance to explore your best ideas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New connections and friendships with people you respect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less back-and-forth hassle and time-wasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, a better working life.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email is one of the biggest daily interactions in your career that somehow goes unnoticed. We think they happen “behind the scenes,” so they don’t really matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the opportunities you missed out on are just half the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also hated the process of seeking out these opportunities. Emails take a long time to write and can frustrate the hell out of you. Sending emails can feel like grinding away on an endless to-do list, leaving you feeling like a spammy robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you enjoyed the process? What if you knew you were delivering value and helping every person you emailed? Sure, you’d earn more money, but imagine if emails also stopped feeling like a chore and instead, became a source of strength for your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know emails aren’t your favorite topic; they’re not mine either. That’s why this book is short. Who wants to read a textbook when you just need help writing an email to a potential client? You’re busy. You have enough to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is designed to be a companion to your email writing process –  something you can open up next to Gmail and use for quick reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you find what you’re looking for, I’ve ordered the book chronologically. How to start writing is at the beginning. How to end your emails well is near the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School, your parents and other well-meaning mentors taught you to do things one way. They showed you how to sell yourself – often at the expense of what your clients need. This book teaches the opposite. Consider it a reset button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t want to make more money or free up more time in your day, then this isn’t the book for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Results speak for themselves. I hope you use this book to unlock your dream clients and projects. If you do, please email me. If you’ve implemented what you read in the book, I’d like to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Robert 
robert@letsworkshop.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-emails-that-win-you-clients&quot;&gt;Why Emails that win you clients?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-story-not-often-told&quot;&gt;The story not often told.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It must be tough for clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re tossed into the web world that even professional designers and developers don’t fully understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They hire someone to create, in a few weeks or months of work, something that their business will depend on every day, forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard client horror stories shared Twitter or websites like Clients From Hell. Now it’s time to share the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Loren owns a sushi catering business in Oceanside, California. It’s called the Sushi Bus, because every weekday, he packs up his business and drives somewhere new to sell sushi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a small business, but he’s able to live off the money he makes. His typical work day is 12 hours long. He works 12 pm - 12 am. He doesn’t have much free time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, his team of chefs focus solely on the art of sushi. They masterfully infuse Mexican, North American, and Vietnamese recipes into their dishes. They are true masters of their craft and dedicate more time to their work than any freelancer I’ve known. Loren barely has time to check his email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it’s a thriving business. Dozens of people ask every day how they can find out where the sushi bus will be next. Customers literally pull out their phones and hand them to Loren, asking to follow the Sushi Bus on Twitter. The problem is, they don’t have an online presence. The Sushi Bus isn’t on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Loren decided to change that. He did some homework and researched how to get a website built. He posted the job on a freelance board and was soon inundated with replies from website designers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, he couldn’t tell them apart. Every email included portfolio and website links, resumes, phone numbers, and more. The applicants used words like “conversion rate,” “php,” “pixel-perfection,” and “mailing lists.” Words he didn’t understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the emails were so long that Loren didn’t even have time to read them. He didn’t know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had even one freelancer mentioned how a great website could open new doors for his business, Loren would have invested immediately. Loren knew a website could help, but he didn’t know how. He didn’t know, because no one told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All he needed to hear was that a mailing list would instantly tell hundreds of hungry fans where to find his bus during their lunch breaks. This would have made total sense to Loren, and he would’ve happily opened his wallet, knowing he would make the money back every time he sent out one of these emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, all the freelancers spoke a foreign language. He felt excluded. He felt like an outsider. His business, his livelihood, and his potential all suffered that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you replied to his job post, you missed out on a great client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the story freelancers don’t share on Twitter. That’s the story this book aims to re-write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;you-dont-need-many-clients&quot;&gt;You don’t need many clients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-only-takes-one-to-end-your-dry-spell&quot;&gt;It only takes one to end your dry spell.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people do nothing when they run out of work. They simply sit and wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others post on Twitter and update their portfolios. These tasks feel like work, but they won’t get you paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do we focus on them? The reason is pretty simple: we’re not used to being direct. We’re used to marketing created by the big guys. They talk to all of us at once, because they need millions of customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have an advantage. You have a much clearer path. You earn money by getting paying clients, so all you need is a handful of customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the big guys, you can afford to get direct with your marketing. You can invest your time and resources in straight-up communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can weigh and measure all of your actions according to how they help you achieve your goal of &lt;strong&gt;getting paid by clients&lt;/strong&gt;. You can ask yourself at any time, “is this directly helping me to reach my goal?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can clearly decide which activities are a total waste of time by asking, “has doing this landed me any clients?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why sending emails has a bigger effect on your career than any other activity. It’s time to do it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many freelancers complain that there’s not enough work to go around – that every online source of work is already inundated, but think about that for a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of job boards on the web, listing thousands of jobs, and millions of people who need a problem solved. Even if you found just one potential client each day, that would would add up to over 20 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you emailed all 20 people this month, using the techniques outlined in this book, you’re almost guaranteed to land one – and that’s only taking job boards into account. The chips are in your favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-need-fewer-clients-and-prospects-than-you-think&quot;&gt;You need fewer clients (and prospects) than you think.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;complexity-loses-games-simplicity-wins-them--vince-lombardi&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Complexity loses games, simplicity wins them.” – Vince Lombardi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In the modern world of business, it is useless to be a creative, original thinker unless you can also sell what you create.” – David Ogilvy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;being-first-doesnt-matter&quot;&gt;Being first doesn’t matter&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Getting an upper-hand on everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of freelancers look at a job board site and think:  
&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;“Why bother? I won’t be the first person in line. There are bound to be hundreds of more experienced freelancers who reply to this posting. I don’t have a chance.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, being first means you’re just slightly ahead of a huge wave of people. That’s not a great position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who post on job boards get a lot of replies, it’s true. But when they get hundreds of replies, they have to take a step back to process it all. The responses can be overwhelming. 
They might even delay the project for a few weeks or months until they can sort out this whole hiring business. 
That’s when it happens. No one who gets a ton of email and thinks they’ll go back and read them all, ever actually does. 
In this case, being first is actually irrelevant. Your email stands apart from the herd if it lags behind by a few days (or even weeks). 
It’s true, you can’t know the perfect time to email someone. &lt;strong&gt;But being first doesn’t matter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The belief is that if your competitor beats you to market, untold riches await them… while your company is now a dead duck. This is rarely true. In fact, more often than not, it’s the other way around. 47% of first-movers fail, compared with only 8% of fast followers. As the phrase goes, you can recognise a pioneer from the arrows in his back.” – Des Traynor, Inside Intercom Blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;start-right-here&quot;&gt;Start right here&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How to keep your email out of the trash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is full of spam. When someone first opens an email (or reads a subject line), they’re thinking, “is this spam?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address this problem upfront. How can you make sure they know your email isn’t spam? Remember that each client you email is potentially worth thousands of dollars, and you only need a handful of clients to make a lot of money. Spend time on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can you invest your time or money upfront to prove your email isn’t spam?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has the recipient written a book or blog post you can read? If so, buy their damn book. Learn their name. Address your recipient by that name. Make a connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead with something you really love about their company. Authenticity means discovering what YOU think is great about them and sharing it sincerely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, as your future client reads each sentence, they only have two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop reading.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step into their shoes and address the fact that their inbox is full of spam. It’s the best way to ensure they keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dont-try-to-convince-anyone&quot;&gt;Don’t try to convince anyone&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## What not to say at the beginning of your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should always respect your recipient’s inbox, but don’t sell yourself short in the process. Don’t try to convince them of something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they’re looking for a local freelancer, don’t say, &lt;em&gt;“I know I’m not local, but remote freelancing really works!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t argue. You can’t convince them. If you want to approach someone, even though you don’t meet a specific requirement, that’s perfectly acceptable – especially if you know you can help them. Don’t let some small detail on their job post stop you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just don’t mention that detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t want to reply through the job board form, that’s fine. Go outside of it. Find the person’s email. Don’t be scared that you’ll piss them off in the process. It won’t happen. 
In fact, it will separate you from the pack. It will prove you care. So do the extra work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And by the way, doing the extra work also means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You learn more about them by reading tweets, blog posts, etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You already know them (and their work) more intimately&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have more ammo to build a real connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;start-at-the-end&quot;&gt;Start at the end&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How to not send babbling, unsolicited emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all had writer’s block. Emailing a potential client is hard. You don’t know what to say. You ramble. You end your email ambiguously, because you don’t know what else to do. That means you end up sending unsolicited, unfocused emails that attempt to:
- Exhibit your expertise
- Leverage your personality or charm
- Share your background info
- Entice them to buy your service
- Show examples of past work
- Give them your resume&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list goes on and on…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all the wrong things to do. You’re not going to charm someone into hiring you. In fact, most of what I listed above has no business in a cold email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s only one purpose. There’s only one outcome you can hope for, which is getting someone to read and reply to your email. That’s the definition of a win in the cold emailing game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t focus on anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about the point of your email. What do you want? Get specific, then write it down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I want this person to be my client”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrong. Not specific enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I want Bob to reply to my email so I can show him how to use this plugin that will help him make a lot of money.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good – and will likely get a reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t think about what you want from the email BEFORE you send it, you’ll start at the top. And the top is typically a greeting and your life story. Too much information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead start at the end. Start with what you want to do, and how that will help your potential client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-to-the-point&quot;&gt;Get to the point&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Stop rambling and write clearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many emails blab on and on. Who cares what they actually say, because no one reads them. They’re lost forever. 
And good riddance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t be there to explain your email, so make it easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t ramble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Here are some random thoughts…”&lt;/em&gt; are the worst five words you can use in an email. I don’t want random thoughts. I just want to read your damn email and get on with my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are you talking about? Talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine &lt;em&gt;you’re&lt;/em&gt; getting the email, and constantly ask yourself: &lt;em&gt;“can you hurry up and get to the point?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the best way to add clarity, because it’s measurable. Don’t tell me you’re better than the rest. Tell me why I should care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is critical. Get to the core of what the client wants. Give them instructions. Remove clutter. Make sure every sentence in the email reinforces your next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-most-people-send&quot;&gt;What most people send&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How to avoid sending the same email everyone else sent already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are extremely predictable. At least 90% send the same email to potential clients, word for word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SUBJECT: I’m a world-class (or some other exaggerated term) freelancer or consultancy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hold it. Let’s stop right there. What the hell is a world-class WordPress development agency? This isn’t the Olympics. If you’re using some exaggerated title to sell yourself in the subject, you’ve already lost. Still, when the poor sap opens the email it continues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello, I’m Robert Williams, the lead developer for (agency name). We’re the leading WordPress agency in (city), and we want to work with the best WordPress sites on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoa, that’s a lot of of jargon. It ignores the fact that we all have our own problems. Your credit card is maxed out, your income taxes are due, your stocks took a tumble yesterday, you upset your SO by forgetting your anniversary, and to top it all off, your doctor just called to tell you you have high blood pressure – not to mention dandruff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you open this email and some sales guy is yapping about what his company wants? He wants to work with the best WordPress websites? Who cares what he wants?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’ve been developing award-winning WordPress sites since 2004, as a top agency year after year. Many clients and agencies around the world have used our development expertise to create a wide variety of sites. Our development skill set includes: wordpress (obviously), html5, css3, responsive design, php, jquery, and mysql.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you even finish reading that? Or did you see a list of skills and immediately skip it? Fuck that shit. And you’re inside this industry. You actually know what those terms mean and you STILL skipped the fuck out of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone who isn’t in the industry might be shocked to know that they even give awards for websites (pretty stupid in my opinion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The person who wrote this email is trying to prove they’re big and rich and on top. So what? As a client, you couldn’t care less about PHP. You have no clue what PHP even means. You’re a 10x developer? WTF is that? Nobody cares if you’re the PHP whisperer. After all, how does it help the person reading the email?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t. The person reading the email only cares about himself, not the person sending the email. The more the sender talks about himself, the more the reader starts to feel small and unimportant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To get to know me better, I would encourage you to check out my website, as well as my LinkedIn profile:  http://mywebsite.com http://linkedin.com/rob&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah yes, the standard, “here’s my website.” What are the chances you click on this thing (besides to peep at it for a sec)? Pretty low. Why? Because you’re the one getting the email. You shouldn’t have to make the effort. Especially since it’s so much easier to delete this email. You’re busy. You’re not interested in looking at some dumbass LinkedIn profile, even if the sender thinks he’s Don Draper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are three recent sites that I developed in WordPress: http://siteone.com http://sitetwo.com http://sitethree.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably looking to hire a WordPress developer because you don’t know shit about WordPress. How will looking at “recent” sites help you? You’re probably not trained in design, development or anything else related to websites, but suddenly you’re supposed to be impressed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let me know if you think our businesses might be a good fit. I look forward to hearing from you and learning how we can best work together. If you can email me back this week to discuss this further, that will be mutually beneficial.  – Robert&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so in addition to all of your stress, job pressure, and daily annoyances, I have the balls to ask you to look at my business and see if I can help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably just as busy as I am (or at least you like to think you are) and now you have to cut time out of your schedule to hunt down, compare and analyse our two businesses – and with a time limit, no less. Fat fucking chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone says that a vague partnership will be &lt;em&gt;“mutually beneficial,”&lt;/em&gt; it’s pretty clear they mean that it will help them, not you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, did I mention how often people send this kind of email? If it’s the exact same email you just wrote to a client today, don’t feel bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not hearing back from potential clients, it isn’t because you’re a bad person or a lousy freelancer; it’s because of the emails you’re writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s change them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;make-the-world-better-with-your-emails&quot;&gt;Make the world better with your emails&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How to ensure people enjoy reading what you write.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, our favorite topic is ourselves – especially when we’re writing emails. Why? It’s easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about ourselves is easy because we know ourselves. It’s even easier to fall into this trap when we’re emailing in order to get something we want. Seeing what we want, right in front of us, is intoxicating. It blinds us with shiny desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing about yourself is intuitive because it feels safer. You’re risk-averse and you don’t want to lose the carrot hanging in front of you, so you don’t make any assumptions about the person you’re emailing. After all, you can’t be wrong if you talk about what you know: yourself. You are your favorite topic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s just one problem: you’re not anyone else’s favorite topic. Their favorite topic is themselves. Every day, people send millions of emails that no one wants to read, because they’re created for the writer, not the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If opening your email felt more like checking the snail mail for something awesome from Amazon and less like digging through the trash, the world would be a better place. If every email you sent contained something awesome that the recipient deeply wanted, everyone would look forward to your emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, if you only received emails with something delightful inside (instead of crappy messages that blabbed on about the sender), you’d look forward to checking your inbox, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;youre-not-alone&quot;&gt;You’re not alone&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Why most emails never get replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sit down to email a potential client, you’re focused on you. You want that new contract. You want to end your dry spell. You want more consulting work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those “wants” come through in your email. Most people send emails focused on themselves. They talk about their talents. They link to their portfolios. They end the email by telling the client how to get in touch. It’s like they’re all alone in the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing emails for yourself doesn’t consider the other person in the equation – and that one-sided attitude comes through in every form of marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, why do freelancers always brag that they &lt;em&gt;“build awesome websites for small businesses.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, why don’t they &lt;em&gt;“build small websites for awesome businesses”&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, it’s not about you or your websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not in a vacuum. Someone else is hiring you. It’s about them. They need something from you. If you think:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to find work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to find the right fit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projects drag on too long.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projects always go over budget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not alone. Clients are tired of this, too, but freelancers never address these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re too busy worrying about getting enough work and why no one is hiring them to make something awesome. They never turn it around to realize that if they’re not getting hired to make something awesome, it means a client doesn’t get that awesome thing, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;address-that-clients-have-a-shitty-deal-too&quot;&gt;Address that clients have a shitty deal, too&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How all projects seem to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, client work can make you sick. With every blown deadline and client snafu, it’s easy to hate some parts of the process. But realize that clients often hate their end of the bargain, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of most projects, they get:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a mysterious price tag&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a long, non-specific timeline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no guarantees it will succeed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address these issues directly. Provide a timeframe for your project. Give them a free sample. Make working with you a no-brainer. Redefine what they need. Take these steps and you’ll create better clients for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, most projects start out the same:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s an inquiry, usually via personal referral, job post, RFP, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next, you qualify the person and the project. You discuss what a mutually beneficial relationship would look like (typically over email).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then you close. Once you agree there’s a fit, you have to line up the numbers and determine the scope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all projects start out the same way, it’s easy to look at the difference between freelancers who succeed and freelancers who struggle at each step. Extract the patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, when freelancers run out of work, they get stuck on step one. They go to message boards and hacker news and ask, &lt;em&gt;“what’s the best job board for freelancers?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful freelancers know the truth: there isn’t one. That’s why everyone who’s looking for the best job board is struggling. It’s the wrong question. Don’t ask it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, ask how you can deliver more value. Look for opportunities to quickly give clients what they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;just-make-the-problem-go-away&quot;&gt;Just make the problem go away&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## The fastest way to win over a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re about to contact a lead, think about how you can make their problem go away. Don’t worry about giving away the farm. In fact, if it makes sense, give them the solution for free. This is how you separate yourself from the pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most businesses already do this, because it works. Basecamp lets you use their service free for 30 days. Costco gives you free samples around every corner. Give a sample of yourself away, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can save a client time, do it. It’s much better than claiming you can help them, because you’ve just proved it. 
Take work away from your clients. Make smart decisions for them and put the burden on yourself to prove that you can help. Ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do they need to get done?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s most important to them?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do they need this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignore everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of worrying about money at this point, think about how you can do some version of what they want for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you take care of their problem by sending this one email?
If so, do it every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;when-theyre-too-vague&quot;&gt;When they’re too vague&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How to connect with people even when you don’t have much to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most job posts include a contact name or email address. It’s rare that they don’t also include the business name. This is all the information you need to do a short recon mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the company founder online. Read his or her blog. Read their Twitter feed. Find business details that you can reference in your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How big is the company?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kind of website do they have?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you tell what it runs on?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with basic information, you can extract potential solutions and phrase them in ways that are almost guaranteed to elicit interest. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”Because you have 13 locations across one state, I suspect you need a streamlined way to do X, which would benefit your company by taking care of Y.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re not 100% sure about what they want or need, your words show that you’re thinking strategically about their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most freelancers won’t take this step because they think they don’t have enough time. You can, because you realize that you only need a few clients. A 10 - 20 minute investment in some basic research can lead to thousands of dollars in client work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you were unable to find &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; information about the company or the person you were contacting, you still have their job post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-their-words-people-are-literally-telling-you-what-they-need-repeat-those-words-back-to-them--and-you-dont-have-to-get-fancy-using-their-words-in-your-email-is-usually-better-than-coming-up-with-something-on-your-own-especially-if-you-dont-have-much-background-info-&quot;&gt;Use their words. People are literally telling you what they need. Repeat those words back to them – and you don’t have to get fancy. Using their words in your email is usually better than coming up with something on your own, especially if you don’t have much background info.  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It pays to listen more than you talk.” – David Ogilvy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;write-about-them&quot;&gt;Write about them&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Where to spend your time when writing an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back, I took a good look at my daily work time. At least 80% of it was spent writing. A blog post here, an email there, some typing in a chatroom, and bam – most of my day was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how much you hate writing, I’m betting your days are much the same. Your business runs on your writing. Your website, your work, and your emails; they’re all based on writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to present your value, you need to focus on your writing. It’s the activity that already occupies most of your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t get me wrong. Although you’re at the center of all this writing, you need to focus on something else in order to improve it. You need to dedicate your time to learning about the person you’re emailing. Their wants. Their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t call this book “send great emails,” because that’s not what you want. Likewise, you shouldn’t send emails saying, “I’m a great freelancer,” because a great freelancer is not what people want to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;not-set-in-stone&quot;&gt;Not set in stone&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Why some people triple their client’s budget while others give discounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re waiting for leads to come in with huge budgets and specification lists that perfectly match your skills, forget about it. Not going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, most freelancers get hung up on this fantasy. The truth is, if you’re a consultant, a big part of your work includes educating your clients. In fact, a job post or another form of outreach is basically just a way to ask for help finding the right solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most successful consultants get it. Instead of complaining about low budgets, they show clients that they have their best interests at heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of discussing the price of open heart surgery, they discuss whether the client needs the surgery at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you approach a client and question whether they even need your service, you immediately put them in a position to fight for what they want. If they’re price-conscious, suggest a smaller project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, you can wow them with a shockingly low sticker price and build their trust by demonstrating that you won’t sell them more than they need. Yes, you’ll get less upfront revenue, but you’re proving that you’re on their side. You increase the odds that they’ll hire you again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might lose a few thousand dollars by suggesting a cheaper route, but you’ll get that 10 or 20 times over on the backend when they realize you were right. After all, would you rather work with someone who’s going to nickel and dime you, or someone who truly has your best interest at heart?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The product itself should be its own best salesman. Not the product alone, but the product plus a mental impression, and atmosphere, which you place around it.” – Claude Hopkins, Scientific Advertising.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sell-an-outcome&quot;&gt;Sell an outcome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Why your portfolio doesn’t help you win work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your portfolio sucks. Even if it’s full of great work, it’s boring. No one wants to look at it. Except you. I don’t care about your history or background. The only thing I’m less interested in is your resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is going to read a 10-page proposal about you and your awesome websites. People don’t want websites. They don’t want to hire a freelancer. They want something to happen. They want a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So focus on selling that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your work can’t sell itself because it puts the cart before the horse. You’re not addressing a client’s needs with portfolio screenshots of your work. It’s like sending your mom in to sing your praises after a job interview. Not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A portfolio doesn’t build a relationship. Instead, it says “check this shit out. Pretty sweet, huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add more context. How does that screenshot of your work highlight what your customer cares about? Will they even understand what you’re showing them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you had to remove the words “I,” “me,” or “my” in the email and replace them with “you,” what would you say?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve helped hundreds of businesses in your position. I helped X-company to accomplish Y-benefit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would become:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Your website reminds me of X-company, which probably means you want Y-benefit as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the benefit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The great Harvard marketing professor Theodore Levitt was known to teach his students, “People don’t want to buy a quarter-inch drill. They want a quarter-inch hole!” Every marketer we know agrees with Levitt’s intuitive insight. But rarely has it changed the way marketers do their work.” – Clayton M. Christensen, Integrating Around Jobs To Be Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;your-client-dgaf&quot;&gt;Your client DGAF&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Why you should write shorter emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading is work. It’s your job to help your clients avoid unnecessary work. Writing shorter emails is the easiest way to get people to read and reply to what you write. Do that and you’ll immediately send better emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might seem counter-intuitive. You know your service will deliver a huge ROI for your client. In your mind, it doesn’t make sense not to care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why you write long emails describing every inch of your work history and past accomplishments. These long, unfocused emails are inconsiderate. They force their way into the reader’s world. They demand to be read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re shitty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write shorter emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I have only made this letter longer because I have not had the time to make it shorter.” ―  Blaise Pascal, The Provincial Letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;short-emails-can-be-shitty-too&quot;&gt;Short emails can be shitty, too&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Length doesn’t matter on bad emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the introduction, I mentioned my service, [Workshop], which is a daily newsletter I send to freelancers that contains a list of the day’s best freelance opportunities on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, my friend Brennan used Workshop to find a freelancer. One of the people who responded sent the following email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Subject: Freelancer  Body: Hi, i’m replying to your post looking for a freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say you should write shorter emails, this is not what I’m talking about. Putting zero effort into the email is a waste of time. Don’t send anything, because you won’t get anything back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most freelancers, however, do the opposite. They send emails like this one (which I received from a freelance accountant):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(img)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge wall of text demonstrates a lack of consideration for the reader – not only because it’s ridiculously hard to read, but because the mere sight of it destroys your will to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This email killed any chance he had of getting hired, even before I read what he had to say. That’s not what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If he had taken just a few moments to format and edit the email, he could potentially have made hundreds or thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“People want to know how your product will be a meaningful addition to their lives. Establishing your product’s value in its attributes (features, performance, etc.) forces people to piece that meaning together themselves. That’s tedious for them and risky for you — how do you know their interpretation will be accurate? When you instead talk in improvements, you’re handing them a complete picture, not a puzzle to put together.” – Samuel Hulick, The Elements of User Onboarding&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;write-like-a-human&quot;&gt;Write like a human&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Why you shouldn’t use scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you tell the love of your life how you feel, it’s real. When you look your parents in the eyes and thank them for raising you, its real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You didn’t pull those words from a blog post, they were real. Be real. Real is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most freelancers send incredibly generic emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You didn’t become a freelancer to lose your soul. You didn’t start a consultancy to speak like a robot. Don’t become something you’re not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone is speaking from the heart, you can tell. You can also smell when they don’t fully believe what they’re saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authenticity is obvious. This holds true, even in emails. Write the way you talk. If you can’t hear yourself saying the words in your email, change them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid scripts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut the jargon and vague promises&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove industry terms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delete stuff no one gives a shit about, i.e. anything that doesn’t directly affect them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-repeat-dont-use-scripts&quot;&gt;I repeat: don’t use scripts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Stop forcing yourself to send bad emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad emails focus on the sender. You can send them to anyone, because the reader is irrelevant. Templates and scripts are, by definition, meant for hundreds, if not thousands of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you’re not writing to thousands of people. You are writing to one person. That’s what makes email one of the most effective forms of marketing on the planet. Don’t abandon that opportunity. The same principle has driven advertising for over 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Do not address your readers as though they were gathered together in a stadium. When people read your website they are alone. Pretend you are writing each of them a letter. One human being to another, second person singular.” – David Ogilvy, Ogilvy on Advertising&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write like you’re speaking to one person, because that’s exactly what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-rid-of-the-bullshit&quot;&gt;Get rid of the bullshit&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Use real terms that everyone understands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a client, you’re not a chief UX research officer, you’re the guy who improves their website or decides what to put on their website. Don’t hide. It’s better to be that guy, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, niche it down even further. What are you really good at building? Instead of being the guy who makes websites, become the guy who’s really good at testing what to put on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s power in specificity. Just don’t get cute. Use real words, not ego-boosting job titles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see way too many websites that say, “we build digital experiences,” or “I’m a digital storyteller,” or use some other fluffy, nondescript language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were a client arriving on this page, I’d think “shoot! I just want a new website,” and close the page – totally missing the fact that these websites could help me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you build websites, you build websites. You don’t craft digital experiences. Pretend you’re explaining it to a five-year-old. That’s how the world will appreciate it. You only have someone’s attention for a few seconds. You only have one chance to connect with them. They won’t immediately understand what you’re trying to say, unless you use familiar words and phrases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speak to clients so they can understand you. Cut the fluff – and the bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whos-we&quot;&gt;Who’s we?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Don’t try to sound bigger than you are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you hear the voice-over in a radio commercial say, “we provide excellent services,” what’s your first thought? Mine’s, “Ugh. Another shitty random company.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you heard your barber or dentist say, “Hey there! It’s time to come see me!” That would be an instant connection. 
Unless you’re referring to someone specific when you say “we,” and the person you’re emailing knows who that is, it’s just confusing. If you’d say “I” on the phone, write that in your email instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying “we” is a way to avoid getting personal. You’re scared that if clients knew you were just a guy on the computer, your business would collapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opposite is usually true. By trying to sound bigger than you are, clients can smell the inauthenticity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what’s wrong with getting personal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;draw-a-line-in-the-sand&quot;&gt;Draw a line in the sand&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Say goodbye to the wrong clients to make way for the right ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late last year I made a big purchase. I needed a car. I decided on a Honda Accord. I read a great book on car buying. I loaded up on information. I learned how to negotiate at car dealerships. I wanted the best deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I started the process of buying a car. There was a lot of back and forth. Many emails were sent. I found several cars that were close to the one I wanted. There was a lot of wheeling and dealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I found the perfect car. It had everything I wanted, but the dealer wouldn’t negotiate. He explained it simply: “we price our cars at the lowest price all the time. Our customers love this about us. We hope you will too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negotiating no longer mattered, because he had exactly what I wanted. Sure, I probably could’ve paid a couple thousand dollars less, but I wouldn’t have been as happy with the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want clients who want the service you provide, not people who are settling because you’re cheaper than the competition. In order to get these clients, you have to be okay with turning the others down. You have to be okay with saying, “if this isn’t right for you, I understand. I find it’s right for the customers I serve.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;your-dream-job&quot;&gt;Your dream job&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## You evolve with more information, so do it consciously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I graduated, I wanted to work at an agency. Then I worked at one. I realized that I wouldn’t be in control of how much money I made and which projects I worked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve turned down multiple job offers from some of the country’s top agencies. Your dream job evolves with information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer, it’s up to you to get that information and control how you use it. Track your efforts. Most of us want to do things our way. Find a way to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Count how many cold emails you send to land one client&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit that number every week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collect the leads you contact in a folder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go back to them later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have this information, your dream job will change again. Knowing how many cold emails you have to send to land one client may not seem hugely important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it’s the key to surviving as a freelancer. It’s one thing that can never be taken away. You can lose all your clients. Never see another referral. But as long as you hit the number, you’re guaranteed to land clients. Making sure you hit that number while enjoying your life becomes your dream job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only this time, it’s what &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;avoid-client-repellent&quot;&gt;Avoid client repellent&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Don’t make it easy for clients to delete your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a reader’s mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Let me know how I can help…”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becomes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Anyway, this was a long brain dump of an email. Not sure what to say next, so I’ll just leave it up to you. What do you think?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand why you might write that to end a long email. It feels professional. What you’re saying, though, is anything but professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re saying you can’t be bothered to figure out how you can help. You’re saying you can’t solve the problems you’re getting paid to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ending an email with this phrase usually means you won’t get a reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reader thinks, “I’m not sure how you can help, either. I’ll give it some thought and get back to them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This. Never. Happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your email will seep to the bottom of their inbox. It will turn cold, dusty, and gray. Weeks or months will pass. Occasionally, the recipient will see it and think, “Oh yeah, that email.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually it will start to chafe at them. Seeing it will bug them. Every passing day the question will loom, “what do I think?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until one day, they’ll shrug and say IDGAF and click delete. They will exhale and never think about you again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The complexity in replying to an email is raised to the power of how many separate requests are made in it: 1 = OK. 2 = next week. 3 = 2016” -  Peter Cooper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;make-it-easy-to-hire-you&quot;&gt;Make it easy to hire you&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Remove any obstacles that come between you and a positive reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are more likely to do something when it’s easy. That’s why you’ve gotta make it easy to read and act on your emails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Break emails up into sections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make them easy to scan by using lists and bolding key points&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove all links unless the client specifically requested them. You’re not trying to drive traffic to a website, you’re trying to get a reply&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t send your entire portfolio. Break out 1-2 pieces that are relevant to their project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Match the benefits of your past work to their current needs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove any job board links. They know they posted on a job board&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t give them a long questionnaire to fill out. No one wants to do it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use good grammar. Write simply and get straight to the point&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’ve agreed on the price and scope, link them to an easy payment system, like Stripe, Shopify, or Gumroad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good rule of thumb: if someone can just reply “sounds good,” then your email does enough of the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means you’ve taken away the hard part: deciding what’s next.
Even busy people will reply if you make it easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-end-an-email&quot;&gt;How to end an email&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Do 80% of the client’s work by outlining the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of repelling clients by asking an open-ended question, use a yes or no question. Why? A yes or no question does 80% of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It saves time. For example, closing an email with, “do you want to see some ideas I have for your site?” means someone just has to reply “sure.” Yet, you’re still giving them control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re prescribing a solution. Do this at the end of every email. It saves time for everyone, but if will feel unnatural at first. You’ll want to slip back into passive mode, because it feels like you’re barking orders. You’re not. You’re doing your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how you will get clients to reply. Here’s what to include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The next step you recommend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A second option, in case they don’t like your first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead up to this in part of your email… or make it the entire email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you’re trying to set the date and time for a meeting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Great! What time works for you?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would become:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Great! I’d love to chat on Tuesday, March 17th at 12 pm PST, but I’m also free Thursday and Friday pretty much all day. When works for you?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cold email to a client would change from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Let me know if you think there’s a fit.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“There are two ways we can move forward: I recommend we do X, because it would mean Y benefit.  If you don’t want to do that, then we can do X and still get Z benefit.  Sound good?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many back-and-forth emails did I just save? A bazillion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;youre-dealing-with-busy-people&quot;&gt;You’re dealing with busy people&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How to get through to busy people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Busy people read emails differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They delete emails without reading them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They archive them before reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think they’re reading every word, but they’re not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They scan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They look for the one question or sentence that sums up the purpose of the email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re constantly thinking, “what does this person want?” And, “does this matter to me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help busy people to reply to your emails:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write simply, one to one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep it short. 75-100 words is plenty for a cold email.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t hide the point of your email. Draw attention to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;busy-people-put-you-in-a-folder&quot;&gt;Busy people put you in a folder&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Follow instructions and follow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Busy people put you in a folder. After they post a job, they dump all the applicants in a folder to look at later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people don’t even make it into the folder. Most job posts have clear instructions about how to apply. Busy people use these instructions as an easy way to sort through the herd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get eliminated is to ignore these instructions. You don’t follow the instructions, you end up in the trash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re in the folder, you’re only halfway there. You have to make it out of the folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to stay there forever? Don’t follow up. If a client sends you an email saying they will follow up soon, that means it’s your job to touch base with them, because they will probably forget to do it. Then guess who will land the project? The person who followed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a great example from e-commerce consultant Kurt Elster. If Kurt hasn’t heard back from a potential client in a week, he sends the following email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Since I have not heard from you on this, I have to assume your priorities have changed.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least 50% of the time, Kurt gets a response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Only write something like this if it has actually been more than a week since you sent the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;get-testimonials-and-referrals&quot;&gt;Get testimonials and referrals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## By minimizing the client’s workload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimizing your client’s workload doesn’t just help you land them, it also helps you land other clients. When I’m coming close to the end of a project, I’ll send an email like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”Oh and by the way, I’m thinking of doing a case study about ProjectName on my website – with your permission. I would also love to include a testimonial from you about my work with :CompanyName: Something like this would be perfect:   “Using Robert’s design services to create a website that measurably attracts more customers is a guaranteed investment. :ClientName: - Founder”  In fact, if you’re busy at the moment, I can use that quote for now. Either way, let me know. Thank you!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works for me 99% of the time, because all a busy client has to say is “yeah, sure,” and bam – the work is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I get a testimonial (which is basically an endorsement to the whole world), I’ll go in and ask directly for a referral:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hey, Thanks for the testimonial. This was an awesome project.  I’d like to continue working with you. I have a few ideas for what we can do in the next few weeks to add to this project and make it even more successful.  I’ll send those over soon, but for now, if you know of anyone who would beneﬁt from a similar service, I would love it if you could send me their email. I’ll let them know that you were thinking this might be right for them, and answer any questions they have about how your project worked out (I’ll also cc you on the email)!  Sound good?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this approach does all the hard work for the client. They simply email me with a name, and I take care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, that’s what clients pay me to do – design strategies that deliver huge results (either in added revenue or time savings) – so I’ve just applied the same principles to my own business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-to-do-next&quot;&gt;What to do next&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Hitting send – and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, what do I do after I send a cold email?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t sit and wait. Cold emailing is a numbers game. A lot of the time, you won’t get a reply. It’s best not to put all of your email eggs in one basket. Applying all the strategies in this book will significantly increase your chance of hearing back, but there’s no way to guarantee that someone will reply to your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow up, but if you still don’t hear back, it’s usually best to just move on to the next lead. In some ways, cold emails are the new job interviews. We’re talking about modern-day interview etiquette here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you only need a handful of clients to be successful, one potential client won’t make or break you. You need to contact numerous people every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick checklist you can refer to before sending your next 10 emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deliver value as quickly as possible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on the client, not on yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sound like yourself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write as short an email as possible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it dead-simple for the client to reply to by suggesting the next step (and an alternative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the past year-and-a-half, I’ve collected hundreds of different questions from freelancers and contractors, and I’ve put all the answers smack on one page. If you’re wondering about something, [you’ll probably find the answer right here].  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;on-your-marks&quot;&gt;On your marks…&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## How to find 200+ leads this month&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now you understand how to send emails that win clients. You know what it takes to deliver value to a client – to focus on them and still sound like yourself. You’re prepared to avoid all the most common mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to spend huge chunks your day sending emails without ever thinking about how you could improve. Now you have a leg up on most other freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, this advice is meaningless if you don’t use it. You might be thinking to yourself, “but I don’t have anyone to email. I don’t know how to find job leads.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not as hard as you think. I find over 200 every month, in just a few hours a day. Here’s how I do it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open up an RSS reader. Import all of the best job boards on the web. To save time, you can use this one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spend 30 minutes a day sorting through the postings to find the ones that apply to you. Look for people who need remote (non-local) freelancers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do some background recon on the ones you want to contact. Get a name, photo, personal email, and links to relevant websites (blog, LinkedIn, Twitter, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow the strategies in this book and send a great email to one person every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-emails-that-win-you-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-emails-that-win-you-clients.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cold emails</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;crafting-a-cold-email-that-sells-your-work&quot;&gt;Crafting a cold email that sells your work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did they hire the specific freelancer they hired?
How’d they find out about the freelancer they hired?
What problems where they having that led them to hiring a freelancer?
What are the results they expected from hiring a freelancer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello [X],&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[Flattery] I’ve just seen the redesign of your website and it’s brilliant – especially [list a specific feature/function].&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[Context] I’m web designer and I was wondering if I could ask you a few quick questions to learn more about how I could best serve your industry.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[Getting to the point quickly] You are definitely a leader in your field, so I’d love to learn what I can – any answers will be kept in the strictest of confidence.
1. What lead you to hiring someone to redesign your website?
2. What results did you expect?
3. How did you find the web designer you hired and why did you hire them?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I appreciate your time and I look forward to hearing back from you,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Frank&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hi Frank,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Our website was outdated and we weren’t able to update it ourselves. Most of our clients also visit our site from mobile devices and it wasn’t responsive.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;We wanted more signups to our firm’s newsletter, which leads to clients hiring us.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;We found Paul (the designer) because he answered a question we had on twitter. 
After seeing his portfolio and feeling like his style was a match for our brand, we hired him.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ms. Lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I hired a designer that understands that sales is the ultimate measure of a good business site. If you don’t understand why I need a high contrast color for the most important button, you can’t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve used a freelancer who does a good job at following directions. I decided to just lay everything out myself [wireframes] and hire a freelancer to design it and a freelancer to chop it up and make it work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I picked my designer because she took the time to understand my business and really cared about the outcome of her design work after the website launched. I’ll hire her again because she quick to reply to my questions and I felt like she had my back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;most-people-think-cold-emails-are-about-what-you-say-theyre-wrong-heres-what-they-are-actually-about&quot;&gt;Most people think cold emails are about what you SAY, they’re wrong, here’s what they ARE actually about&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cold emails aren’t about what you say, here’s what they ARE about&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people believe the most important thing about writing emails is the writing, they’re wrong&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it makes sense right. When you open up your email editor to write something you’re faced with a blank screen. Of course that’s intimidating. You open it up, maybe start writing a few sentences, but before you know if you’ve deleted and rewritten the email more than a dozen times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This experience leads us all to believe that what really matters is the words we send. If we just send the magic key email with the secret passphrase it’ll unlock the client work. Every client has a project safe word that if they hear they’ll instantly spread open their wallet for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that sounds ridiculous that’s because it is. Yet most freelancers believe that! That’s the only real feedback loop we get. Our minds tell us the only difference between email 1 and email 2 are the contents. The truth is that just under the surface there’s difference, subtle yet powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s not throw writing completely out of the window. It’s not that simple. If you write a 4k word email that takes months to read you probably won’t hear back. And you can dramatically increase the amount of replies you get by simply avoiding a few other common mistakes like ending your emails with “let me know…” I cover ALL of the mistakes later in the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what I’ve found to be the true MOST important factor in winning work through cold client outreach is actually something that’s unseen in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is timing not as conscious of a decision as the words we use, it’s nearly invisible when you factor in that it’s completely unique to the client. The mindset, the literal time in their locale, the stage of the buying cycle for the client all of these things have a greater affect on whether they decide to hire you than what you write in your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve written a book on writing great emails so I’m not here to tell you what to do, I believe a great email improves your chances greatly, I’m just here to tell you what works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we just said, timing is nearly invisible to you. So how can you even account for timing? Well it’s impossible to get every single email perfectly timed, that’s true. But you can maximize the effectiveness of your emails by accounting for just a few different timing challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first timing challenge is busy overload. If a client is overloaded with other work, other applicants, other things going on then the chances that this is the right time to send them an email are REALLy really low. He’s likely drowning to catch up with his work, not looking to respond to your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next timing challenge is buying cycle. The client might not be ready to buy from you because they’re not ready to buy from anyone. They’re simply not at t point where hiring someone makes sense… yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next timing challenge might literally be the time. If a client checks their email in the morning but you send it at night their time then you probably won’t get your email read until the following morning if at all. The chances they reply go down with how long it takes them to get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to all of these challenges is sending multiple emails. Following up. Most people never do this, so they never get the right to be heard. They send a one-off email and they expect people to flock to them. As I’ve demonstrated this simply isn’t going to win you enough work. You’ll constantly be fighting off one of these timing struggles. You’ll get lost int the shuffle of the busy, the time, or the buying cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you send more than one email though, your chances of getting through dramatically increase. In fact they double :D because you’re giving yourself a chance to break through the timing issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now probably the best part about all of these is that you can automate it so simply so that al you have to do is send the one off email and automatically you’ll also be scheduling a follow up campaign to get sent however often you like for as long as you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not bad right? There’s a few different options you have for email providers but the one I’ll use in this example is Quickmail.io I recommend you use quickmail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use my 5x5 approach for all your outreach sending a total of at least 5 email followups to your original email and you use at least 5-day wait period between followups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will mean you truly get the most out of the emails you send. I’ve seen similar campaigns like the one linked in the lesson notes get a 40% response rate. Why? Because this campaign takes account for the most important aspect: timing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see what you think of as spammy or annoying is actually the most considerate thing you can do. (Clients will actually tell you that even after the 5th email you send them “oh wow thanks so much for following up with me I’ve been out of town but this is really important so I appreciate it”)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5x5 technique protects you from over-doing it. 5 days is the minimum amount of time you should wait before you send another followup email to someone. You don’t want to be too quick because then you come off as needy. You want to be cool calm and persistent. By calmly following up every 5-10 days, you’re showing you not only understand that the client buying process is rocky and that they’re busy people , you’re also showing you can be counted on to do what it takes to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-take-cold-email-from-good-to-great&quot;&gt;How to take cold email from good to great&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi Rob&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope yo pare good?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just wondering if you can help me out? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t normally do this as it feels a bit cheeky, but I would really appreciate your help and advice here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After buying your’ emails’ book and reading it through several times, I am still having issues with the way I draft my emails. I am a designer, not a copywriter, which really doesn’t help!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wondering if you could tel me how you think this email works for you if you have 5 mins - mo worries if not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks
Steve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subject: Hi Matthew, I want to help you find new business leads at your worldwide exhibition events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Matthew, I came across the SPI Lasers website while on LinkedIn today, and really like what the business does and noticed that SPI Lasers attend some exciting exhibitions around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I own a growing design and marketing agency and thought it might be worth us having a meeting to see if we can help you out with your exhibition and promotional work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally I would like to meeting you in the next couple of weeks, so would it be ok to arrange a meeting with you today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey Steve, 
 
Thanks for buying the book! I don’t normally do full email breakdowns (you know how it is, once you do one 100 people ask) but since I have some free time…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subject: Hi Matthew, I want to help you find new business leads at your worldwide exhibition events
 
This is a great title. However, it is a little long and getting lost in the inbox. I just sent it to myself in gmail and it barely fits in the title bar, with some of the most intriguing parts almost at the end. Have you ever heard the expression “don’t bury the lede”? I think that applies here. 
 
I’d think about shortening this down to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi Matthew – a tip for you on finding more leads at the exhibitions you attend &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this will give you better results because it’s intriguing the person to click on this email. I want to click on this email and see what the tip is you’re promising. It will at least warrant a click. From there, it’s your job to bring it home (which we have to do). 
 
 Hello Matthew, I came across the SPI Lasers website while on LinkedIn today, and really like what the business does and noticed that SPI Lasers attend some exciting exhibitions around the world.
 
This is good. It’s pretty standard, you might not have to add anything but I might shorten it a bit and add something personal that you can add quickly. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Matthew,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across the SPI Lasers website on linkedin this morning – and really like ! I also noticed that SPI Lasers attend some exciting exhibitions around the world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you’re already inserting a custom first name and business name into this email you’ll probably find it not too hard to come up with something basic yet personal about each company you can use to really drive home the point that this is a hand-written email you took the time to craft. (More on automating this part to make it super quick below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I own a growing design and marketing agency and thought it might be worth us having a meeting to see if we can help you out with your exhibition and promotional work?
 
I’m not sure I like how you’re asking for the meeting here. it comes off unconfident and unconvincing. Might be worth? if you’re not sure it’s worth it, why are you emailing? I also don’t care if your design agency is growing I care if my business is growing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead I’d try a different approach (see below). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you go on to ask for a meeting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally I would like to meeting you in the next couple of weeks, so would it be ok to arrange a meeting with you today?
 
Kind regards
 
Steve
 
I think you’re rushing the process here. A first email is a very fast way to expect a meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead I’d change the ask completely. Right now you’re asking someone (who’s probably extremely busy btw) to not only make time to read this email and reply but you’re also asking them to open up their calendar,  take time out of their schedule, and commit to doing something with that time that may or may not give them any value at all…. THAT’S A TOUGH ASK. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s dial it back. Instead i’d switch to a different ask all together. First, you haven’t established that this is the right person you’re talking to. A lot of people might have someone who specifically handles the exhibitions, and you’re barking up the wrong tree. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you haven’t given them anything of value yet to warrant this person to try helping you or allow them to give you time on their calendar or even a reply. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I’d try instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know as you prepare for each exhibition it’s tempting to just rehash the same old exhibition and promotional materials – what MOST companies do – but I’ve found that my clients are actually shocked when they see how much more cost efficient it can be to personalize or tailor a new presentation to each venue (sometimes it’s even cheaper than re-using old stuff!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And considering the amount of time and money you have to invest to attend these, a sharp increase in the amount of {desired result} by grabbing a couple low hanging fruits can make a lot of sense!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you the right person to discuss this with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve
(Link to your email course: 5 ways to maximize your exhibition booths)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can obviously tweak the part about tailoring a new presentation to whatever it is that YOU area actually offering, I just took a stab in the dark…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here you’ve delivered value. You’ve opened their eyes and already have potentially made them a huge return or saved them money by alerting them to this fact. You’ve given away some of your best piece of advice in your email. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you’ve done this, a prospect is way more likely to respond. They’re now in your debt … and it takes away the scammy or salesy vibe from the email because you’ve just demonstrated that you have their best interest at heart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to use this exact script, you can definitely revise or make it your own but I think following these principles will make this email template way more profitable! It takes your email from good to great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and - this is important - if you haven’t done this yet, I’d also make sure I automate this sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, I’ve used quickmail.io to create the followup sequence for you (there’s a button at the bottom you can use to copy this sequence directly into your account). I’ve even dropped in your (revised) cold email into this template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just following up with quickmail will automatically 5x your response rate if you’re currently not following up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welp! there’s my value bomb for the day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, i’m in the process of revising the book from scratch with a bunch more examples, and case studies i’ll be sure to send it your way once it’s ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be interested in leaving a testimonial, it’s clear you’ve implemented the material great!
 &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-cold-emails.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/writing_emails/2017/06/05/writing_emails-cold-emails.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>writing_emails</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Re-activating customers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an email sent to me 6(?) months after I used their service. It felt like a nice way to touch back with someone who had used their service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently don’t do this enough, so I want to use this email as a way to follow-up with past customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Robert&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We hope you’re doing well. Over the last week we’ve collated a solid list of all our ‘hot’ (meaning very experienced!) virtual staff that are currently looking for work by teaming up with Virtual Staff Finder.
Here’s a list of all the qualified ‘experienced’ VAs:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Podcast Editor 2 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Audio/Video Editor 10 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Web Developer 8&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Web Designer 7&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Graphic Designer 10&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Copy Writer/Content Writer 4&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	High-End SEO 8 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Digital Marketer 10 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Ecommerce VA 8&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Project Manager 12&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Bookkeeper 8&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	Executive Assistant 6&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;•	General Virtual Assistant 90 - HIGH DEMAND POSITION&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And - these are all experienced staff, waiting to be hired.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you’re currently looking to hire for any of the roles above, simply hop onto the site and sign-up - one of our Relationship Managers will be in touch with you as soon as your order comes through and you’ll be well on your way to hiring the VA you need to help run, support and growing your staff.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reply to this email - we’re here to help!
Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Team VSF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/service/2017/06/05/service-reactivating-customers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/service/2017/06/05/service-reactivating-customers.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>service</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
