<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop - The best freelance job leads emailed to you daily.</title>
    <description>Get over 200+ hand selected freelance web consulting leads sent to your inbox every week</description>
    <link>http://letsworkshop.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://letsworkshop.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 09:23:46 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 09:23:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Workshop!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;hello-and-welcome-to-the-wonderful-world-of-finding-clients&quot;&gt;Hello and welcome to the wonderful world of finding clients!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay maybe finding clients isn’t so wonderful sometimes. In fact, it’s mostly just a time-consuming pain in the butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s why you’ve hired me. All day long you work with clients. They get to tell you what &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; want and &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; get to deliver them results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-its-your-turn-to-be-the-client&quot;&gt;Now it’s your turn to be the client.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I want to do everything in my power to deliver YOU results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is this welcome packet. Please consider it a personal thank you gift for signing up for Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve loaded it up with as many valuable goodies as possible to get you off on the right foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ive-built-workshop-for-one-reason-to-help-you-make-more-money&quot;&gt;I’ve built Workshop for one reason: to help you make more money.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe you’re already on the right path. Soon you’ll be boosting your revenue and ending the feast or famine cycle forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How? By reaching out to new clients daily. This is an excellent way to find new freelance projects for your business. In fact, if you reach out to just one job in every Workshop email,  you’ll have contacted 20 potential new projects in just one month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combined, that equals less than an hour of work per month in exchange for potentially earning tens of thousands. In fact, a few Workshop rockstars have closed six figure deals in their first few months. (Talk about return on investment.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-whats-next&quot;&gt;So what’s next?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-leads-will-start-arriving-shortly&quot;&gt;Your leads will start arriving shortly.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll get the first few over email in the next hour along with periodic check-ins and tips from me in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The daily email containing about 8-10 of the latest freelance leads will arrive every weekday at 8:00 AM EST.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you email those leads as soon as you get them no matter what!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, you might be fully-booked right now, and although that seems like it’ll last a long time - the truth is dry spells happen because freelancers often don’t look for work when they should (like when they’re already fully booked).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I recommend if you’re not booked 6-months in advance, you email at least one new lead every day. Even if it’s not a lead you found on Workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-ill-be-doing-for-you&quot;&gt;What I’ll be doing for you&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;im-finding-you-the-best-freelance-leads&quot;&gt;I’m finding you the best freelance leads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a little bit of custom software and a ton of elbow grease to go through the web and find you potential clients. I use a custom built rss reader, a gigantic list of freelancer sites, and more levers and systems to keep track of everything everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My small team and I find leads in the very best freelance job boards like Authentic Jobs, Dribbble, Hacker News threads, and more. This means the opportunities you receive are public. This is a good thing because they’re readily expecting to receive emails from freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wont send you anything from Elance or a similar job boards because those are usually 1) not open to the public (meaning you have to sign in and compete on their websites to see them) or 2) really low quality (meaning they wont be good clients).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of time it takes to find these is really what you’re paying for. On average you’ll save over 10 hours per week. This is not an exaggeration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added up, that’s a 5-10x savings for you based on your hourly rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see a low-competition lead come in (with a green ‘low-competition’ label indicator), that means it’s someone who’s come to Workshop to find a freelancer. These are usually the best people to email because there’s almost no competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-makes-a-good-lead&quot;&gt;What makes a good lead?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​The leads you’ll be receiving are 100% organic, gluten-free grass-fed beef. (Sorry if you’re hungry now). What I’m trying to say (poorly) is that the leads I find are from public places. They’re people actually looking for a freelancer at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means they’re clients who realize they need help and already have a project in mind. This makes them much better than “cold leads” who a lot of freelancers contact out of the blue, without knowing if they’re even interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good lead boils down to someone who needs a problem solved. It doesn’t matter what your specialty is, if you can solve a problem for a client they don’t care if you do it in ruby, php, or klingon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelancers can get hung up on the fact that they specialize in X and forget the fact that this means nothing to 99% of people on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And sometimes a client won’t understand the difference between a Wordpress website and a Ruby app. It’s your responsibility to decide what the right solution is, regardless of what they’re asking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-wont-get&quot;&gt;What you won’t get&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be real honest with you. You are not ever going to receive the absolute ideal client from me. Why? Because  the perfect client doesn’t exist. There will never be a lead that checks off every thing you want to see in a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is we create ideal clients by working with them. By educating them. By demanding them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only working with great clients is something I’m a huge proponent of. However, the leads I send - and any leads really - are all focused on one thing: getting the most successful project. Regardless of what their budget says, you can help these leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is most clients honestly don’t know what it takes to create the right solution. Everyone wants a deal, and to get the lowest price on something. However, if you’re able to show them why it’s in their best interest to pay more there’s not a single client in the world who won’t open up their wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They all have a problem they want solved. You’re ahead of most because you’ve paid to have these people brought to you. You value your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s time to give clients what they value. Stop focusing on what clients say they want. Make it about improving their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you do this, the specifics, like they think their budget is, will melt away.
See, this opens you up to more clients, but it also makes you more valuable. It makes you a consultant, valued for your mind just as much as your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I suggest you stay signed up and push yourself to contact at least one new opportunity every day, regardless of if it’s your ideal lead. Even if you think they can’t afford you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of writing off clients that you think you aren’t right for, propose a solution that shows you are. This is how top freelancers get clients to 10x their budgets. By showing them what they need, not what they ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;before-you-reply-to-any-leads-i-send-you-read-this&quot;&gt;Before you reply to any leads I send you, read this&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know there are bad clients out there. But consider for a second that it must be tough for clients too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re tossed into the web world that even professional designers and developers don’t fully understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They hire someone to create, in a few weeks or months of work, something that their business will depend on every day, forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long after you are working on the next project, they’re still using with what you made for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard client horror stories shared on Twitter or websites like Clients From Hell that tell the side from a freelancer’s perspective. Now it’s time to share the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Loren owns a sushi catering business in Oceanside, California. It’s called the Sushi Bus, because every weekday, he packs up his business and drives somewhere new to sell sushi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a small business, but he’s able to live off the money he makes. His typical work day is 12 hours long. He works 12 pm - 12 am. He doesn’t have much free time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, his team of chefs focuses solely on the art of sushi. They masterfully infuse Mexican, North American, and Vietnamese recipes into their dishes. They are true masters of their craft and dedicate more time to their work than any freelancer I’ve known. Loren barely has time to check his email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it’s a thriving business. Dozens of people ask every day how they can find out where the Sushi Bus will be next. Customers literally pull out their phones and hand them to Loren, asking to follow the Sushi Bus on Twitter. The problem is, they don’t have an online presence. The Sushi Bus isn’t on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Loren decided to change that. He did some homework and researched how to get a website built. He posted the job on a freelance board and was soon inundated with replies from website designers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, he couldn’t tell them apart. Every email included portfolio and website links, resumes, phone numbers, and more. The applicants used words like conversion rate, wordpress, pixel-perfection, content, online presence, and email marketing. Words he didn’t understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the emails were so long that Loren didn’t even have time to read them. He was left contemplating his options. He didn’t know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had even one freelancer mentioned how a great website could open new doors for his business, Loren would have been interested. All he needed to hear was that a mailing list would instantly tell hundreds of hungry fans where to find his bus during their lunch breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… And Loren would’ve invested immediately. This would have made total sense  and he would’ve happily opened his wallet, knowing he would make the money back every time he sent out one of these emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, Loren knew a website could help, but he didn’t know how. He didn’t know, because no one told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, all the freelancers spoke a foreign language. He felt excluded. He felt like an outsider. His business, his livelihood, and his potential all suffered that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you replied to his job post, you missed out on a great client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so-whats-the-right-way-to-email-a-lead&quot;&gt;So, what’s the right way to email a lead?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-cold-email-checklist&quot;&gt;The Cold Email Checklist:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you hit send on an email, make sure what you’re sending is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of freelancers get hung up on what they should say to a new prospect. Staring at a blank screen can be a horrible feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’ve developed this cold email checklist after studying thousands of ignored emails and why they didn’t get responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to just dive in and write a quick, short rough draft email to your prospect. For more help with that, check out my book: Emails That Win You Clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your first draft email written, you can apply a few quick rules to it to make sure you’re maximizing your response rate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/subject.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The subject line should be so specific it could only be sent to one person in the world.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will make sure your email gets opened because busy people look to remove spam first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/length.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The length of a cold email should be under 120 words.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Busy people don&#39;t have time to read much. Make it simple, crisp, and get to the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/value.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Your email should provide something of value.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Would you be happy to receive this email, even if you had no intention of hiring someone? Delivering advice or tips is an easy way to show you&#39;re on the client&#39;s side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/social.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Don&#39;t include links to your social media or portfolio.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;A prospective client doesn&#39;t really care about your work... at least not yet. The only point of this first email is to get them to reply so making them click on your website, linkedin profile or portfolio doesn&#39;t help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/clarity.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; It should be easy to find the point of your email.
	&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Someone using a job board probably has a lot of email responses and is more likely to scan and look for the next step. Make that part of your email easy to find. Bold it if you have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/reply.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The end of your email should be easy to reply to in seconds.
	&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t want to give a busy lead more work. If the lead can say &quot;sounds good&quot; you&#39;re probably on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;free-claim-your-premium-bonus&quot;&gt;Free: Claim your premium bonus&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-complete-guide-on-writing-emails-to-cold-leads-and-landing-more-work-in-less-time&quot;&gt;My complete guide on writing emails to cold leads and landing more work in less time.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write emails that win you more freelance work in less time with my book.  As a premium member you can get the book for free (I usually sell it for $79).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the coupon code: WKSHPPREMIUMJD7K
(And dont share this with anyone it’s your own personal code)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;your-primary-contact-person-is-julie&quot;&gt;Your primary contact person is Julie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like providing the absolute best service available anywhere. To do that I’ve built a team that will help you build your freelance business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your personal email-writing concierge is Julie Elster. She’s written for me in the past, spoken at the Double Your Freelance Conference, and has a great service that helps freelancers get paid faster called Just Tell Julie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into any questions, need help thinking something out, or anything else email her directly for the fastest response time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;julie@letsworkshop.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-availability-to-you&quot;&gt;My availability to you&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the last section, Julie is your main point of contact with the service. I’m super excited to offer her expertise to you and her email writing services alone are worth your entire subscription cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work Monday through Friday, between 9am and 5pm Pacific Time. If you email me outside of those times, I might not respond as quickly as usual. Also, I only meet during business hours. See how my time zone lines up with yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everybody, I also take vacation from time to time. You will continue to receive leads when I’m on vacation as long as it’s not a national holiday. However, I will most likely not be as easy to get a hold of during this time. I take vacation time really seriously and think it’s crucial in maintaining a high level of service for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most folks, I also take a few holidays off. Expect intermittent availability around most American holidays, especially Thanksgiving, Christmas, New Year’s, MLK Day, my birthday (February 01), Memorial Day, the Fourth of July, and Labor Day – and no leads on these days either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to hear about everything you like and dislike about using Workshop. Clients like you are my lifeblood and it’s crucial to hear what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need assistance click here to email me at robert@letsworkshop.com or call me personally at  760-693-3360.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to having you as a customer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/rob-sig.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 7em; margin: 1em 0 0em; display: block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 09:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/welcome-packet</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/welcome-packet</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are big client projects losing you money?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I won’t touch projects that have budgets smaller than $30,000. Anything lower is usually low-quality and unprofitable for me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a statement I get periodically from freelancers who pay me to send them leads. I’m not sure why $30,000 is the magical number for quality and profit but apparently it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I really don’t get about this statement is that it’s usually coming from a freelancer, aka a one-person business, who’s overhead costs are essentially zero (yes I know you pay $20/month for project management software).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Couple that with the fact that these people claim to be “desperate for work” and sometimes even in a dry spell and it’s even more confusing. Still most of these freelancers “won’t touch” a large portion of potential projects because initial budgets are too low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this is outrageous. In what world are we living where a $5,000-$10,000 project is unprofitable for  one-person? Is the problem here really a dollar amount that’s too low, or is it that you don’t know how to make a project of any size profitable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-problem-with-big-budgets&quot;&gt;The big problem with big budgets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure 5-figure projects look great at first. You’ve got a far away deadline and a big wad of cash. At the start, the possibilities seem endless. However, these big projects also end up hurting freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, the big price tag pushes hiring companies into thinking they own you. You’re simply more demanding when you’re paying more money and unless you’re actively pushing back on this, you’ll naturally give in to more client requests for the same reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when you feel scope creep start to kick in. You feel pressure to say yes to features and other requests that you don’t truly believe should be implemented because hey you’re getting paid a small fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People naturally want more bang for their buck. When you finally deliver the work, there’s endless revisions. Deadlines come and go without actually shipping anything. Projects drag on and on. Each day carving both you and your client’s profitability away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why if you’re not able to make a $5,000 project profitable, you’re less likely to make a larger, more complicated project profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, what exactly about a larger amount of work is easier to scope out and turn a profit on? Larger projects are by definition harder to make profitable because there’s more work to… try make profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I think freelancers should focus on making smaller projects more profitable before they move on to large ones. If you can make a 5,000 projects profitable for you and your clients, you can also make a 5-figure budget profitable for you and your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-you-delivering&quot;&gt;What are you delivering?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think everything you’re delivering on those big $30k+ projects is essential. However, have you really examined what exactly is bringing your costs up so high that you can only afford to take on 5-figure projects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think you’ll find most of your budget goes to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Research&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proposals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Revisions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outsourcing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emailing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and Following up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you cut the bulk of these costs and replaced them with nothing? Would the client be worse off? If not, then you should do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will make your business more viable. It will make your client’s business more viable. It’ll give you less of a headache. You’ll be able to focus on things that actually matter instead of fluff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Won’t cutting these things make you less money?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Everything listed above is also hard to quantify. That’s why it’s hard to scope a large project accurately. You might think these things all carry a high margin but I disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think if you really examined them, you’d find out they’re not that profitable for you either. The work that matters is what’s implemented. Do more of that and less of everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Productize the way you present stuff, ask for feedback, onboard your clients and more. Create a better experience for them by systemizing the way clients work with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;decide-what-matters&quot;&gt;Decide what matters.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can taking less money be a good idea?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quote from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/freelance/comments/35lpsc/i_charge_30k60k_for_wordpress_websites_with_a/&quot;&gt;great reddit thread&lt;/a&gt; about a guy who’s charging $50,000 for simple Wordpress websites with nothing much to them. Nothing much except what matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Should customers care about brand? Yes. But should they care about it more than sales? 80% of businesses fail in the first year, and I’m guessing a big part of it is paying someone $50 an hour to make a 10 page website that generates a net zero result for their business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great point. Yes the point of this reddit thread is that he charges even more than $30,000 dollars but what’s important is that he’s focusing on value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can accomplish the same results by focusing only on what matters you can charge more. You can also make all projects more profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is figuring out what is valuable to client. To start limit your work to two things. Things that will either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make them more money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save them more money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you find ways to work for less and still make it more profitable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;present-it-as-a-package&quot;&gt;Present it as a package.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what some high-value consultants are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://landingpageinaday.com&quot;&gt;Jarrod Drysdale will create an extremely affordable landing page that converts for you in a day.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://websiterescues.com&quot;&gt;Kurt Elster will makes your ecommerce site make more money than it does now.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://draft.nu/revise/express/&quot;&gt;Nick Disabato will tear down your site’s usability for $600.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all world-class designers charging less then a few thousand dollars for a valuable service. These are services that are profitable for a business of any size. (Even freelancers could benefit from hiring them at this price.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is an interesting point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever considered hiring a freelancer like you for $30,000? Why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it’s truly a great investment why aren’t you paying for it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a B2B service provider, it’s also in your best interest to make sure your service provides a profit for your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s important to ask if the money you’re getting paid is a sound investment for the company who’s hiring you. By taking it are you really helping the company you’re being hired to help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that kind of self-critical price analysis is what we should be doing with our service on a normal basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I think dabbling in creating a service offering where you’re actually charging less is smart. Especially if it means you’re working with a company you can actually help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would allow you to say no to more projects. It would open you up to working with different types of businesses that could have never afforded you before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clients you might actually enjoy working with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-step-for-you&quot;&gt;Next step for you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s never been a better time to be a designer or developer. You’re in demand. You build websites and apps and things that are valuable. So valuable in fact, people will pay you a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(While I do agree that some highly-specialized consultants shouldn’t work for less than $X0,000 – I don’t think that’s the case for 90% of people. Probably including you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you should always charge more. Of course you should double your rate today. Of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe the current pricing model for freelancing is not all it’s cracked up to be in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you do if instead you had to make a $3k project profitable?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specifically, what would you have to cut out?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would it make sense to hire yourself? Could you afford it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why not? How will the type of project you usually get hired for not be profitable for you as a client?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you change that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;great-reading-to-help-you-keep-thinking-about-your-profitability&quot;&gt;Great reading to help you keep thinking about your profitability:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/freelancing&quot;&gt;The Client Burnout Rescue Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mariepoulin/designing-your-customers-experience-5b44c80fc564&quot;&gt;Why you need to design your customers experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@monteiro/13-ways-designers-screw-up-client-presentations-51aaee11e28c&quot;&gt;13 ways designers screw up client presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/class&quot;&gt;Get Paid! How to make projects more profitable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://letsworkshop.com&quot;&gt;My lead-generation service called Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 01:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/profits</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/profits</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deleted my portfolio, made $30k in six months</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2012, I was working full-time, for a pretty large company, where I was the only member of the entire marketing department. Although I was making a nice salary, I didn’t feel like my time was valued. This only worsened when new management was brought in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, the new boss called me into his office to “chat,” and I distinctly remember thinking “God, I hope I get fired.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I even sat down, a man I had only known for 2 weeks took a deep breath and let me know I was getting let go. (This came only 2 months after receiving a raise for my ‘great performance with the company’ — go figure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was left with the same 3 options that basically every designer has:
Work for an advertising/design agency.
Work for another company or startup.
Start my own freelance business, full-time.
After meditating on my options, and laying on the beach for a week, I came to the conclusion that I would try to make freelancing my full-time business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first 6 months I ended up making about $30k. That may not seem like a lot to you, but it was a huge liberation to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I did it… and full disclosure, I took an online course called Earn1k and followed it precisely. Click here for more info on that course by Ramit Sethi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I decided to start my own business, my mind shifted — I began to look at everything I did as a strategic system for getting new clients.
Once I did this, I realized I needed to stand out. If I was going to reach clients more effectively than the average designer online, I needed to have a better strategy. So, I looked at all the freelance designer portfolios online — aka my competition. Most had good to great design, all with a similar look and the quality. Honestly, they were not too different from my own work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They all had very minimal copy, and usually a short designery phrase like, ‘Pixel perfection,’ or whatever. You know. You’ve seen them. Basically, sites like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I came to the conclusion designers were focusing on portraying a “cool” image that they wanted to see in themselves, not exactly the professional, trustworthy image that potential clients wanted to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided I didn’t need a portfolio website.
This meant, that if a potential client wanted to see my work, they would have to ask me directly, and I could send them a pdf. (I even deleted all but one of my dribbble shots). This allowed me to keep track of every single person who wanted to see my work, enough to merit an email to me anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also forced me to put an emphasis on the words I used in my emails, and eventually things like meetings, proposals, and other forms of communication. These things are all typical to the client on-boarding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lead to me crafting an offer specifically designed for people I wanted to work with.
In order to do this I had to decide on my ideal client. I looked at the online communities and thought about which groups were most in need of design, and also had the ability to pay for my services. I decided to target Startups, because they seemed to have the biggest need. They also fit perfectly in my price range, being that I was semi-inexperienced freelance designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when I sat down to write my first emails, I avoided broad terms other designers might use to describe their work. I found a lot of designers describing their work to clients generically like “I do great design.” I decided to learn niche phrases to startup culture like “conversion rate optimization,” and “lead generation,” instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most effective things I did for my business during this time was focus on one thing: getting clients.
This is something that came easier for me because I ran a one person freelance business with a very clear goal — earn money by getting clients. However, having laser focus on one goal is still something that most businesses should take note of. Especially if you have limited time. It prioritized everything I did, because I was able to ask myself ‘is this directly helping me reach my goal?’ — at any point in my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This focus allowed all my energy and time to be dedicated on the most important thing to my business: making money. Almost as important, it allowed me to see what areas were a total waste of time. Things that weren’t directly helping me generate revenue were killed… this included; twitter, facebook, blogging, dribbble, reading emails etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It still came down to me contacting people directly.
Other things, like twitter, might work for some people, but I’m simply saying they didn’t work for me. What worked was emailing people directly. I put together a script using the tailored offer that I crafted and sent it out to dozens of startups throughout the six months. I used one site in particular for over 15k of my revenue, Folyo — a curated job board by Sacha Greif.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there were other, less-prolific job boards like craigslist, freelance switch, and others, but the main idea was that I was using the same specific script to send out to many people. It felt so much better than sitting on my laurels and just posting stuff on twitter or dribbble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped letting the success of my business depend on outside forces like others contacting me.
Because of this, I was able to track where my efforts were getting the biggest return. I created an excel file, for tracking leads. Every time I sent a new lead an email, I would update the file for that particular lead source. If I heard back, I would again update the file. Soon I was able to see which of these job boards were responding with the highest frequency (Folyo), and put all my effort there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also prepared for the future. Whenever a lead would email me back even if just letting me know they were going with another designer, I would put them in a new folder — a pool of past leads to follow up with in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This pool quickly became my most valued source for new work.
Starting and depending on my freelance business taught me that you can’t listen to what other people say will work for you. If you do what everyone says you should do, you’ll be doing a little bit of everything. Couldn’t hurt could it? Well as Ramit said in his course, “OF COURSE IT CAN HURT.” To be a successful freelancer I needed to focus on one thing, getting more clients, not everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Constantly updating my portfolio website, tweeting, and posting dribbble shots, might have felt like I was working on my freelance business, but in the end it was just a distraction. Contacting people directly has had other benefits too, like allowing me to charge more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 01:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/deleted</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/deleted</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to build a profitable sales funnel</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;first-off-what-is-a-sales-funnel&quot;&gt;First off, what is a sales funnel?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process that every freelance project goes through to land you a paying client. This includes how you win and find work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-most-sales-funnels-look-like&quot;&gt;What do most sales funnels look like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every freelancer’s sales funnel is identical. You find a client online or through referral and proceed with a disorganized, inconsistent courting process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-inquiry&quot;&gt;Pre-inquiry&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is where a client or freelancer find one another. This can happen in a variety of places, like your portfolio, a website, referral or job posting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;inquiry&quot;&gt;Inquiry&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is usually an &lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot; class=&quot;off-site&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://letsworkshop.com/phone-calls&quot;&gt;phone call&lt;/a&gt; made expressing interest in working together. Typically, this is inquiry is pretty short and simple, containing contact information and a little background on the project or freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;inquiry-review&quot;&gt;Inquiry Review&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The freelancer and client will each assess whatever information they’ve been given about working together, and if desired, schedule some sort of follow up meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;first-meeting&quot;&gt;First Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The freelancer and client meet over Skype, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsworkshop.com/phone-calls&quot;&gt;phone call&lt;/a&gt;, or in person to discuss the project. Both sides give a rough idea of what they’re looking for, and receive a solid understanding of what working together will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal&quot;&gt;Proposal&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Usually you, the freelancer, will sit down to put together some sort of proposal that will put ink to paper about what is expected.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-review&quot;&gt;Proposal Review&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The client will receive your roadmap and possibly ask to refine/change it. This is usually a string of emails, questions, and back-and-forth about the project until most details are ironed out.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;revised-proposal-if-asked-to-change-first-proposal&quot;&gt;Revised Proposal (if asked to change first proposal):&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The freelancer will either present or send over a revised proposal. This may include a contract and invoice, at which point the client will either accept, decline, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsworkshop.com/freelancer-negotiation&quot;&gt;negotiate&lt;/a&gt; a lower rate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;the-actual-work&quot;&gt;The actual work&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is when you will begin work on the project, usually starting by learning as much as possible about the project and company you’re working with. Once you have adequately researched the project, you’ll begin creating the deliverables you and the client agreed upon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-i-improve-my-sales-funnel&quot;&gt;How can I improve my sales funnel?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to improve your sales funnel you must first identify what each step of the process looks like for you. Some freelancers might get most of their inquiries from referrals, others might use job boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve identified how your sales funnel is unique, you can identify where the problems are, like at what step potential clients are dropping off. Here are some good questions to start:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step are you deciding whether to take on a project?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Is there a better point in the sales funnel to do this?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step is a client’s decision to hire you made?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At what step do you want a client to make their decision?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step do you think you’re ready to give a price quote?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Have you ever given a price before this step?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If so, how can you ensure this doesn’t happen?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you putting too much importance on any one step? (hint: it’s step 8)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you eliminate as many steps as possible without losing clients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/sales-funnel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/sales-funnel</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to make 2x more than other freelancers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Freelancers tend to beat around the bush when it comes to money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s common to ask “what’s your hourly rate?” when what you’re really interested in knowing is how much a freelancer makes (and particularly how much more/less they make than you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An hourly rate can be deceptive. All it gives you is a number. You’re left to piece how much they actually make, where they find work, and other important questions alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s one of the reasons I surveyed hundreds of freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My survey asked three basic questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much do you make per month?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you do when you run out of work?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much of your work comes from each source?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;border-cell-only&quot; style=&quot;margin: 4em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;th colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
			The average freelancer based on survey results...
		&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			earns &lt;strong&gt;$3,590&lt;/strong&gt; USD a month before taxes
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			gets &lt;strong&gt;2.46&lt;/strong&gt; inquiries from their website per month
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			makes &lt;strong&gt;61%&lt;/strong&gt; of their income from referrals
		&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;border-row-only&quot; style=&quot;margin: 4em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;When out of work they...&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;th&gt;Percent&lt;/th&gt;		
		&lt;th&gt;Income&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;th&gt;Difference&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;

	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Email prospects&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;12%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$5,515&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td class=&quot;good&quot;&gt;+91%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
		
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Look for work on a job board or marketplace&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$3,257&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;+13%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;

	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Turn to their social media or network&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;40%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$2,920&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;+1%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Do nothing or wait&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;24%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$2,316&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td class=&quot;bad&quot;&gt;-20%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-results-were-clear-the-people-who-went-directly-to-prospects-by-emailing-them-made-almost-2x-more-than-everybody-else&quot;&gt;The results were clear: the people who went directly to prospects by emailing them made almost 2X more than everybody else.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, twice as many freelancers do nothing during a dry spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why do only 12% of people go direct, when it’s clear it works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is it that it takes a lot more work to do outreach and when you’re used to billing hundreds of dollars for an hour of your time – spending that much time on something else besides billable work just isn’t the best use of your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why the rest of the course below will walk you through how to make this process 10x faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/earnings</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/earnings</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to double your cold email response rate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of freelancers get hung up on what they should say to a new prospect they’re cold emailing. Staring at a blank screen can be a horrible feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’ve developed this cold email checklist after studying thousands of emails and why they got ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to just dive in and write a quick, short rough draft email to your prospect. For more help with that, check out my book: &lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot;&gt;Emails That Win You Clients&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;once-you-have-your-first-draft-email-written-you-can-apply-a-few-quick-rules-to-it-to-make-sure-youre-maximizing-your-response-rate&quot;&gt;Once you have your first draft email written, you can apply a few quick rules to it to make sure you’re maximizing your response rate:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/subject.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The subject line should be so specific it could only be sent to one person in the world.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will make sure your email gets opened because busy people look to remove spam first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/length.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The length of a cold email should be under 120 words.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Busy people don&#39;t have time to read much. Make it simple, crisp, and get to the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/value.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Your email should provide something of value.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Would you be happy to receive this email, even if you had no intention of hiring someone? Delivering advice or tips is an easy way to show you&#39;re on the client&#39;s side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/social.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Don&#39;t include links to your social media or portfolio.&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;A prospective client doesn&#39;t really care about your work... at least not yet. The only point of this first email is to get them to reply so making them click on your website, linkedin profile or portfolio doesn&#39;t help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/clarity.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; It should be easy to find the point of your email.
	&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Someone using a job board probably has a lot of email responses and is more likely to scan and look for the next step. Make that part of your email easy to find. Bold it if you have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;border: 5px solid #2996bf; border-radius: 1em; padding: 1em; margin: 2em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/checklist/reply.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; margin: 0 1em 0 0; border-radius: .25em;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: 1em 0 .5em 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-check-circle&quot; style=&quot;color: #36b744;&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The end of your email should be easy to reply to in seconds.
	&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t want to give a busy lead more work. If the lead can say &quot;sounds good&quot; you&#39;re probably on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-your-email-passes-all-of-these-rules-it-is-probably-ready-to-send-and-youll-have-a-30-50-chance-of-response-form-a-client&quot;&gt;If your email passes all of these rules, it is probably ready to send and you’ll have a 30-50% chance of response form a client.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You still have to land one of them. So how do yoy find a list of prospects you can email right now?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/cold-emails</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/cold-emails</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use job boards to find hundreds of leads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I started a service that finds hundreds of freelance leads for a small group of ambitious consultants specializing in design and development work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group uses my leads to earn hundreds of thousands of dollars every year. Yet, 99% of them are available for free online. In fact, anyone could find them and land the same projects for free all by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hiding this, I’m going to walk you through exactly how I find leads every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-post-it-note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note about Workshop:&lt;/strong&gt; If you don&#39;t want to do this all yourself, you too can use my service to skip everything below and just have it done for you. You&#39;ll jump straight to the part where you have a limitless amount of amazing freelance projects in your email every day. Just sayin. &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Try Workshop today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heres-how-to-use-job-boards-to-find-an-endless-supply-of-leads-each-month&quot;&gt;Here’s how to use job boards to find an endless supply of leads each month:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-gather-your-supplies&quot;&gt;Step 1: Gather your supplies.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patience and perseverance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An RSS reader.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few hours a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-search-for-freelance-job-boards-and-compile-them-into-an-rss-feed-reader&quot;&gt;Step 2: Search for freelance job boards and compile them into an RSS feed reader.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to find high quality job board on the web and compile their RSS feed into an RSS reader (I recommend feedly). If you want to skip this part and just get to the Step 3 you can download my Instant Lead Generator below and plug it into your favorite RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;featured-product&quot; style=&quot;border-top: 1px solid #888; border-bottom: 1px solid #888; padding: 2em .5em; font-size: 80%; margin: 3em 0;&quot;&gt;
	
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/instant-lead-generator.png&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 30%; margin: .5em 1em 5em 0;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;display: table;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h3 style=&quot;margin: .5em 0;&quot;&gt;Instant Lead Generator&lt;/h3&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;This file will save you hundreds of hours of work. Simply plug it into any RSS reader and enjoy thousands of freelance job opportunities at your fingertips. It would take you a really long time to compile this list of job boards on your own. I&#39;ve spent years compiling this list and searching high and low in every nook and cranny of the web to build this monster.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;This file comes pre-loaded for you with a huge chunk of job boards. It&#39;s what I use to find thousands of high-quality freelance leads for Workshop. You&#39;ll get a ready to go OPML file that you just need to import into an RSS RSS reader to instantly monitor every job board that houses freelance leads.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;$19.95&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://gumroad.com/l/instant-leads&quot; class=&quot;buy-link&quot; style=&quot;width: 6em; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Buy now&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-browse-the-rss-feeds-and-pick-the-low-hanging-fruit-first&quot;&gt;Step 3: Browse the RSS feeds and pick the low-hanging fruit first.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for projects that look like ideal fits first. I recommend starting with established job boards like Authentic Jobs and Behance. When it comes to this, getting started is half the battle. Don’t think you have to find hundreds of people to email every day. Instead, be consistent about finding 1 or 2 new opportunities daily. This should only take minutes to create a constant flow of warm prospects coming into your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that ultimately it’s a numbers game, and burning out by contacting a billion leads on your first day won’t produce great results. Once you pick the 1 or 2 low-hanging, most desirable projects, contact them immediately. Later you can go back and find more if you have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you open up feedly and see one or two project you’d like to work on, contact those before moving on. Here’s a video of me doing this process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7hHlh3yKUp0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro-tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Use additional search criteria when available, terms like ‘remote’ and ‘freelance’ will skip all the location-specific or full-time listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-find-niche-job-boards-that-apply-to-your-specialty&quot;&gt;Step 4: Find niche job boards that apply to your specialty.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some job boards don’t offer an RSS feed. This means you have to go through their site by hand. While more time consuming, these sites are the home of some of the best freelance projects - especially if they relate to something you specialize in. To cut down on time, get familiar with where each job board keeps important details like location preference, budgets, and project type. Building up a familiarity with these niche job boards takes time, but there are so many new job boards popping up that there are constant opportunities to land work. Don’t look for ideal clients, instead look for people that need a problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s some examples of niche job boards:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=seeking%20freelancer&amp;amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&quot;&gt;Hacker news seeking freelancer threads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://larajobs.com&quot;&gt;LaraJobs for PHP, Laravel jobs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://djangojobbers.com/&quot;&gt;Django jobbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.railsjobs.com/&quot;&gt;Rails Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gotten the hang of this process and begin to land work consistently from job boards, you’ll find that it really doesn’t require you doing the work. In fact, since your hourly rate is pretty high it not make sense for you to do this entire thing yourself anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hell, even if you’ve never done it yourself and want to skip the learning curve of curating and hand-picking leads from job boards, and get straight to the awesome part high quality consistent freelance leads, you’ll want to outsource it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could hire a general purpose VA for $500/month+ or you could pay Workshop (my highly specialized service) to do it for you for a fraction of cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save 4-5 hours a week and just get the best consulting opportunities on the web delivered to your inbox! Starting at only $99/month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, using the steps outlined above you can generate steady client work just using job boards. This 1-on-1 outreach is powerful because you don’t have to rely on outside forces to win work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;now-that-you-have-hundreds-of-leads-at-your-fingertips-you-might-be-wondering-how-to-keep-track-of-it-all-thats-what-well-cover-next&quot;&gt;Now that you have hundreds of leads at your fingertips, you might be wondering how to keep track of it all. That’s what we’ll cover next:&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/using-job-boards</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/using-job-boards</guid>
        
        <category>finding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use Twitter to find leads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’re probably not friends with the hundreds of people who turn to twitter looking for help on projects everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why the most common thing freelancers do when they want to find work VIA Twitter yields no results. It’s usually tweeting something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey friends, I’m available for projects!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hey guy - I’m looking for freelancer work..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;help … someone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Followed by waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach is like expecting to find your next client by yelling into an echo-y cave with no one in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, if you wanted to find the love of your life and had no clue where they lived, who they were, or anything about them you probably wouldn’t post a notice at a supermarket saying seeking love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead a sounder approach would be to actually approach someone who appears to be a match, directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: you might text or call someone who gives you their number. You might approach someone at a bar or a dating website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are better options than the grocery store posting because they’re going to where the fish are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of expecting fate to intervene, you’re giving yourself the best chance. You should do the same with twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why post in your empty silo that is your twitter audience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, If you want to harness the power of twitter, try using something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://topsy.com&quot;&gt;Topsy&lt;/a&gt;. Searching through all the clutter on twitter can take hours and you probably wont find very much via their default search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, a service like Topsy can help you customize and sort your search more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to using words like freelance, design, and development - add words like “email” (to find people who leave behind an email address). Follow up with them over email instead of just on twitter. You can also set reminders and notifications via google alerts or tweetdeck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to sort through the multitudes of tweets out there by finding keywords people use when tweeting out for help and approaching them directly in a one to one setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not expecting your desperate tweets to bring in work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/market-twitter</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/market-twitter</guid>
        
        <category>market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to respond to RFPs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any RFP I’m interested in, I ask them one simple question. If they can answer it directly, I’ll move forward. If not, I move on. In the last year, I’ve responded to two formal RFPs. I lost both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth of RFPs is they’re usually written with an agency in mind. I know, I’ve been the guy they were written for before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RFPs are an interesting animal. From my experience, most of the marketing folks involved with sending an RFP out for bid don’t even want to do it… they have to. I have a rather pleasant ongoing contract with a large state organization in PA, and they were smart enough to use their 1-year extension option with my contract to avoid having to send this out for bid yearly. Every other year, however, they are required by the state auditor general to do this RFP crap… just like every other state funded organization in PA. They don’t have to choose by price, and in the end they get to make the final call so long as it fit’s their budget plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Kurt Elster said, the RFPs are written with someone particular in mind for the job (me). It’s nice to be on the inside of that situation, but they are difficult to respond to for folks on the outside looking in. Sometimes you just get lucky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, when it comes to RFPs, I always weigh the value of the project against the time and hassle involved. If it’s an ongoing contract, I usually give it a little more consideration. I’m a big fan of guaranteed income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moral of the story is that hatred for the RFP is mutual in a lot of instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Corey Tiani&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people who do the best with RFP’s (and are actually the people who’ve made $100k+ from workshop) are the ones who have a system in place for replying to RFP’s specifically. They either hire someone to help, or have developed such a templated and refined process that they can do it themselves in a fraction of the time. This usually means they see it as a numbers game and don’t sweat it when they don’t hear back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/requests-for-proposals</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/requests-for-proposals</guid>
        
        <category>market</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use masterminds as a freelancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a member of Workshop’s Mastermind group, I’ve shared knowledge, business practices, and what’s working for my businesses with other freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, four of us in the Mastermind group got to chat via Google Hangout and swap some stories. It was such a unique opportunity to sit down and chat with other designers and developers… something that unfortunately doesn’t happen all that often. I think we all get so busy with our work and what we’re producing that we forget to reach out and connect with others in our industry – and that’s perhaps one of the most important things we were lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started by introducing ourselves and how we got to where we currently are in our business. We had a variety of skill levels, from someone doing front-end development for about a year to a back-end developer who had been going since 1999. We talked about our ideal clients, what we’re working on now (and how it’s going), and what challenges we’re facing in our businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed how we can improve our skills and really hone our craft to become better designers and developers. I’m really looking forward to getting to know these guys and sharing what I learn from working with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Alex,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across your website on twitter and I really love your work. You’ve been behind so many of my favorite designs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a freelance designer and illustrator as well, but I’ve struggled to find new clients lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you mind sharing a few tips on how you would look for new work (if you were starting out)? I’m always curious about how fantastic designers do things and 1 or 2 minutes of your time would be insanely valuable to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make: I hate networking. Most networking events leave me feeling somewhere between “so unclean I need to take a shower clothed” and “there isn’t enough xanax in the world to be cool right now.” Okay, I’m exaggerating, but networking events are rough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for people like me, mastermind groups are the ultimate networking hack. A mastermind group is a group of like-minded individual who meet regularly (usually once a week) to help each other out. Mastermind groups are even better when the people involved are from the same industry, working toward a common purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to have Rob, reach out to me, and ask if I’d like to help run a new mastermind group for Workshop. Rob and I have bounced idea’s off each other before, and as usual, I thought it was a great idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastermind groups have three great purposes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;PROBLEM SOLVING: Any question you ask, can be potentially solved by the group as a whole. Businesspeople and freelancers often feel like they’re going it alone, the mastermind group is also a support group. Even if they can’t solve a problem, the group can at least work out next steps to solve a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;ACCOUNTABILITY: Every meeting closes with sharing each member sharing a goal they’d like to accomplish. The next week, they have to report to the group the status of that goal. Being held accountable is a powerful motivational tool that entrepreneurs often miss out on there own.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;NETWORKING: Everyone’s combined connections become the group’s total networking power. Have a problem that I know my colleague can solve? I’ll introduce you. That spirit of fraternal collaboration empowers the group.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this isn’t my first mastermind group, this was my first meeting with the Workshop Sales Funnel Mastermind group, and I’ve already come with new business contacts, new friends, and even some actionable advice to promote my business. I’m looking forward to future conversation with the group, I can’t wait to see what we accomplish together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/masterminds</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/masterminds</guid>
        
        <category>finding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
