<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshop - The best freelance job leads emailed to you daily.</title>
    <description>I help ambitious freelance web consultants find and win new clients by sending them over 200+ leads each week. I hand select each lead for quality.
</description>
    <link>http://letsworkshop.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://letsworkshop.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 14:18:33 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 14:18:33 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Start here</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-do-dry-spells-happen&quot;&gt;Why do dry spells happen?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a freelancer or consultant you’ve probably noticed your business is plagued by a vicious feast or famine business cycle. This means that all of the time you have to look over your shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day you live in fear that an untimely bill will put your checking account over the edge and in the red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know that dry spells poke holes in your income, business trajectory, and sanity. Yet you probably don’t know the true cause of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;its-not-why-you-think-dry-spells-are-not-a-natural-part-of-freelancing&quot;&gt;It’s not why you think. Dry spells are NOT a natural part of freelancing.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not entirely anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s true there are natural ebbs and flows to any sales cycle – long periods without work don’t occur just because.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They happen because of specific actions you take (or don’t).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think back to the last time you were stressed out about not having any work. It probably kicked your butt into high gear. In fact, that’s probably the last time you dedicated whole days to looking for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made you desperate and you probably hated that feeling… but guess what? It also probably worked. After all, you made it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever gone through a rough patch only to later have way more clients than you can handle come to you for work all at once?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to throw your hands up and curse: &lt;em&gt;“Oh sure NOW everyone wants to hire me. Where were all of these clients 2 weeks ago?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you don’t realize, though, is you caused it. If you hadn’t waited until you had no work to start a mad dash of client outreach, you could have totally avoided this situation altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-truth-is-dry-spells-actually-begin-when-youre-fully-booked&quot;&gt;The truth is dry spells actually begin when you’re fully-booked!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why the trick is to not wait until you’re out of work to do something about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds easy, so why don’t freelancers do it? Because when you have work you’re too busy to look for leads. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you might be thinking: sure this all makes sense but if I’m too busy, then I’m too busy – and forcing myself to keep up with an endless treadmill of sales activity doesn’t sound like something I want any part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thats-why-you-need-to-break-your-freelance-sales-cycle-into-a-set-of-small-actions-you-can-do-in-15-20-minutes-every-day&quot;&gt;That’s why you need to break your freelance sales cycle into a set of small actions you can do in 15-20 minutes every day.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, just like client projects tend to go way over the timeline you have in your head at the beginning of a project, the income you get from them won’t sustain you as long as you think it will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you know it you’ll be out of money, and still have to finish up the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That results in a huge loss all around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse, relying on sheer willpower to create sales won’t work. That’s why your inbox is distraction central instead of a sales machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need a system that you can follow effortlessly, no matter how busy you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-enough-with-feast-or-famine-heres-how-well-build-your-pipeline&quot;&gt;So enough with feast or famine. Here’s how we’ll build your pipeline:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will walk you through how to go from paycheck-to-paycheck freelancing to booked 6-months out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each chapter will break down a specific way you can find clients, pitch them effortlessly, and win work TODAY - so you never have to worry about where your next project will come from again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to sign up and get 10+ high quality freelance leads looking to hire someone like you, right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s absolutely free, and I’ve hand-checked each lead for quality to make sure they’re all 1) looking for a freelancer, not an employee 2) open to working remotely with a freelancer anywhere 3) have a specific project they need help with 4) have a budget of at least $1000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also included every lead’s contact info like email, twitter, website and photo so you can envision yourself working with them before you ever contact them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;im-tired-of-dry-spells-and-feast-or-famine-freelancing-im-ready-to-build-a-more-stable-freelance-business&quot;&gt;“I’m tired of dry spells and feast or famine freelancing. I’m ready to build a more stable freelance business.”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;form class=&quot;drip-opt-in free-course-signup&quot; action=&quot;https://www.getdrip.com/forms/9298754/submissions&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; data-drip-embedded-form=&quot;1306&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;name&quot; name=&quot;fields[name]&quot; value=&quot;&quot; placeholder=&quot;Your name&quot; /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; class=&quot;sample&quot; name=&quot;fields[email]&quot; value=&quot;&quot; placeholder=&quot;Your email&quot; /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Show me my future clients&quot; data-drip-attribute=&quot;sign-up-button&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I used your tips and landed gigs in less than 2 weeks and am currently in talks with 3 more!”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;– Glori Surban, Designer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;after-you-get-the-leads-youll-also-get-my-trusted-system-for-finding-emailing-and-winning-work-absolutely-free&quot;&gt;After you get the leads, you’ll also get my trusted system for finding, emailing, and winning work absolutely free.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method behind the course is called the CALM freelancing method and it’s designed to make it easy to load up your work pipeline by breaking down daily sales into small actionable steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s four rules that make up the CALM method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact a new lead everyday:&lt;/strong&gt; Because you’re a freelancer you don’t need thousands of clients - you really only need a handful. Contacting at least 20 leads a month (or one per day), means you’ll have all you need in new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always put yourself in the client’s shoes:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s hard to email someone when you don’t know who to contact or what to say. Instead of trying to come up with something from scratch, I’ll show you how to pull words from your prospects mouthes and write something compelling so they’ll respond every time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line up work 3–6 month’s into the future:&lt;/strong&gt; Because most of us think dry spells start when we run out of work, we don’t prepare during times we actually have work. I’ll show you exactly what to do so your sales activity doesn’t just stop when you land a client.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make it automatic:&lt;/strong&gt; The CALM method can take up a lot of bandwidth if you don’t prepare by automating it wherever possible. You’re busy running a consultancy, and if you can’t imagine doing even more on top of all of this you’re not alone. I’ll show you how to create a sales system that runs on its own and allows you to sleep great at night instead of stressing over your business.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;signed-up-good-lets-move-on-to-chapter-2&quot;&gt;Signed up? Good. Let’s move on to Chapter 2.&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/freelancing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/freelancing/</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sales funnel 101</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-sales-funnel&quot;&gt;What is a sales funnel?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process that every freelance project goes through to land you a paying client. This includes how you win and find work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-do-most-sales-funnels-look-like&quot;&gt;What do most sales funnels look like?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every freelancer’s sales funnel is identical. You find a client online or through referral and proceed with a disorganized, inconsistent courting process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-inquiry:&lt;/strong&gt; This is where a client or freelancer find one another. This can happen in a variety of places, like your portfolio, a website, referral or job posting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inquiry:&lt;/strong&gt; This is usually an &lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot; class=&quot;off-site&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://letsworkshop.com/phone-calls&quot;&gt;phone call&lt;/a&gt; made expressing interest in working together. Typically, this is inquiry is pretty short and simple, containing contact information and a little background on the project or freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inquiry Review:&lt;/strong&gt;  The freelancer and client will each assess whatever information they’ve been given about working together, and if desired, schedule some sort of follow up meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Meeting:&lt;/strong&gt; The freelancer and client meet over Skype, &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsworkshop.com/phone-calls&quot;&gt;phone call&lt;/a&gt;, or in person to discuss the project. Both sides give a rough idea of what they’re looking for, and receive a solid understanding of what working together will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal:&lt;/strong&gt;  Usually you, the freelancer, will sit down to put together some sort of proposal that will put ink to paper about what is expected.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal Review:&lt;/strong&gt;  The client will receive your roadmap and possibly ask to refine/change it. This is usually a string of emails, questions, and back-and-forth about the project until most details are ironed out.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revised Proposal (if asked to change first proposal):&lt;/strong&gt;  The freelancer will either present or send over a revised proposal. This may include a contract and invoice, at which point the client will either accept, decline, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsworkshop.com/freelancer-negotiation&quot;&gt;negotiate&lt;/a&gt; a lower rate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The actual work:&lt;/strong&gt; This is when you will begin work on the project, usually starting by learning as much as possible about the project and company you’re working with. Once you have adequately researched the project, you’ll begin creating the deliverables you and the client agreed upon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-can-i-improve-my-sales-funnel&quot;&gt;How can I improve my sales funnel?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to improve your sales funnel you must first identify what each step of the process looks like for you. Some freelancers might get most of their inquiries from referrals, others might use job boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve identified how your sales funnel is unique, you can identify where the problems are, like at what step potential clients are dropping off. Here are some good questions to start:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step are you deciding whether to take on a project?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Is there a better point in the sales funnel to do this?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step is a client’s decision to hire you made?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At what step do you want a client to make their decision?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At what step do you think you’re ready to give a price quote?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Have you ever given a price before this step?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If so, how can you ensure this doesn’t happen?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you putting too much importance on any one step? (hint: it’s step 8)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you eliminate as many steps as possible without losing clients?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/sales-funnel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/sales-funnel</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your freelance income</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Freelancers tend to beat around the bush when it comes to money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s common to ask “what’s your hourly rate?” when what you’re really interested in knowing is how much a freelancer makes (and particularly how much more/less they make than you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An hourly rate can be deceptive. All it gives you is a number. You’re left to piece how much they actually make, where they find work, and other important questions alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s one of the reasons I surveyed hundreds of freelancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My survey asked three basic questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much do you make per month?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you do when you run out of work?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much of your work comes from each source?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;border-cell-only&quot; style=&quot;margin: 4em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;th colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
			The average freelancer based on survey results...
		&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			earns &lt;strong&gt;$3,590&lt;/strong&gt; USD a month before taxes
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			gets &lt;strong&gt;2.46&lt;/strong&gt; inquiries from their website per month
		&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;
			makes &lt;strong&gt;61%&lt;/strong&gt; of their income from referrals
		&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;border-row-only&quot; style=&quot;margin: 4em 0;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;When they&#39;re out of work most say they...&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;th&gt;Percent&lt;/th&gt;		
		&lt;th&gt;Income&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;th&gt;Difference&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;

	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Email prospects&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;12%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$5,515&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td class=&quot;good&quot;&gt;+91%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
		
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Look for work on a job board or marketplace&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;15%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$3,257&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;+13%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;

	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Turn to their social media / network&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;40%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$2,920&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;+01%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
	
	&lt;tr&gt;
		&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;Do nothing or wait&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;24%&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td&gt;$2,316&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;td class=&quot;bad&quot;&gt;-20%&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-results-were-clear-the-people-who-went-directly-to-prospects-by-emailing-them-made-almost-2x-more-than-everybody-else&quot;&gt;The results were clear: the people who went directly to prospects by emailing them made almost 2X more than everybody else.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, twice as many freelancers do nothing during a dry spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why do only 12% of people go direct, when it’s clear it works?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is it that it takes a lot more work to do outreach and when you’re used to billing hundreds of dollars for an hour of your time – spending that much time on something else besides billable work just isn’t the best use of your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why the rest of this course will walk you through how to make this process 10x faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lets-get-started-sending-better-emails-in-less-time&quot;&gt;Let’s get started sending better emails in less time.&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/freelance-rate</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/freelance-rate</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 minute email checklist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of freelancers get hung up on knowing exactly what to say to a new prospect that they’re cold emailing. With the limitless options to what you can include in a cold email, it can be a daunting task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’ve developed the cold email checklist after years testing and seeing thousands of emails from freelancers get ignored to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to just dive in and write a quick, short rough draft email to your prospect. For more help with that, check out my book &lt;a href=&quot;http://emailsthatwin.com&quot;&gt;Emails That Win You Clients&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;once-you-have-your-first-draft-email-written-you-can-apply-a-few-quick-rules-to-it-to-make-sure-youre-maximizing-your-response-rate&quot;&gt;Once you have your first draft email written, you can apply a few quick rules to it to make sure you’re maximizing your response rate:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔	Click display images to see this picture	
The subject line should be so specific it could only be sent to one person in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will make sure your email gets opened because busy people look to remove spam first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔	Click display images to see this picture	
The length of a cold email should be under 120 words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Busy people don’t have time to read much. Make it simple, crisp, and get to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔	Click display images to see this picture	
Your email should provide something of value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be happy to receive this email, even if you had no intention of hiring someone? Delivering advice or tips is an easy way to show you’re on the client’s side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔	Click display images to see this picture	
Don’t include links to your social media or portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prospective client doesn’t really care about your work… at least not yet. The only point of this first email is to get them to reply so making them click on your website, linkedin profile or portfolio doesn’t help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔	Click display images to see this picture	
It should be easy to find the point of your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone using a job board probably has a lot of email responses and is more likely to scan and look for the next step. Make that part of your email easy to find. Bold it if you have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔	Click display images to see this picture	
The end of your email should be easy to reply to in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to give a busy lead more work. If the lead can say “sounds good” you’re probably on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your email passes all of these rules, it is probably ready to send and you’ll have a 30-50% chance of response form a client. That’s just a response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You still have to land one of these, so that still leaves you begging the question. how do I find a list of prospects I can email on everyday?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;next-lets-dive-into-the-most-effective-ways-for-finding-leads-in-the-second-section&quot;&gt;Next, let’s dive into the most effective ways for finding leads in the second section:&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 16:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/intro-email-checklist</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/intro-email-checklist</guid>
        
        <category>intro</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Job boards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I started a service that finds hundreds of freelance leads for a small group of ambitious consultants specializing in design and development work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group uses my leads to earn hundreds of thousands of dollars every year. Yet, 99% of them are available for free online. In fact, anyone could find them and land the same projects for free all by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hiding this, I’m going to walk you through exactly how I find leads every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-post-it-note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note about Workshop:&lt;/strong&gt; If you don&#39;t want to do this all yourself, you too can use my service to skip everything below and just have it done for you. You&#39;ll jump straight to the part where you have a limitless amount of amazing freelance projects in your email every day. Just sayin. &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Try Workshop today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heres-how-to-use-job-boards-to-find-an-endless-supply-of-leads-each-month&quot;&gt;Here’s how to use job boards to find an endless supply of leads each month:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1-gather-your-supplies&quot;&gt;Step 1: Gather your supplies.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patience and perseverance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An RSS reader.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few hours a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2-download-my-a-hrefhttpwwwletsworkshopcomdownloadsendlessclientscheatsheetopmlendless-lead-generatora-and-plug-it-into-your-favorite-rss-reader&quot;&gt;Step 2: Download my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.letsworkshop.com/downloads/endless_clients_cheatsheet.opml&quot;&gt;Endless Lead Generator&lt;/a&gt; and plug it into your favorite RSS reader.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This file comes pre-loaded with a huge chunk of job boards that I’ve collected over years of finding freelance leads. It’s an OPML file so all you need to do is import into an RSS reader and you can instantly monitor almost every job board that houses freelance leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-3-browse-the-rss-feeds-and-pick-the-low-hanging-fruit-first&quot;&gt;Step 3: Browse the RSS feeds and pick the low-hanging fruit first.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for projects that look like ideal fits first. I recommend starting with established job boards like Authentic Jobs and Behance. When it comes to this, getting started is half the battle. Don’t think you have to find hundreds of people to email every day. Instead, be consistent about finding 1 or 2 new opportunities daily. This should only take minutes to create a constant flow of warm prospects coming into your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that ultimately it’s a numbers game, and burning out by contacting a billion leads on your first day won’t produce great results. Once you pick the 1 or 2 low-hanging, most desirable projects, contact them immediately. Later you can go back and find more if you have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you open up feedly and see one or two project you’d like to work on, contact those before moving on. Here’s a video of me doing this process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7hHlh3yKUp0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro-tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Use additional search criteria when available, terms like ‘remote’ and ‘freelance’ will skip all the location-specific or full-time listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-4-find-niche-job-boards-that-apply-to-your-specialty&quot;&gt;Step 4: Find niche job boards that apply to your specialty.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some job boards don’t offer an RSS feed. This means you have to go through their site by hand. While more time consuming, these sites are the home of some of the best freelance projects - especially if they relate to something you specialize in. To cut down on time, get familiar with where each job board keeps important details like location preference, budgets, and project type. Building up a familiarity with these niche job boards takes time, but there are so many new job boards popping up that there are constant opportunities to land work. Don’t look for ideal clients, instead look for people that need a problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s some examples of niche job boards:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hn.algolia.com/?query=seeking%20freelancer&amp;amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;amp;prefix&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;dateRange=all&amp;amp;type=story&quot;&gt;Hacker news seeking freelancer threads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://larajobs.com&quot;&gt;LaraJobs for PHP, Laravel jobs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://djangojobbers.com/&quot;&gt;Django jobbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.railsjobs.com/&quot;&gt;Rails Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gotten the hang of this process and begin to land work consistently from job boards, you’ll find that it really doesn’t require you doing the work. In fact, since your hourly rate is pretty high it not make sense for you to do this entire thing yourself anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hell, even if you’ve never done it yourself and want to skip the learning curve of curating and hand-picking leads from job boards, and get straight to the awesome part high quality consistent freelance leads, you’ll want to outsource it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could hire a general purpose VA for $500/month+ or you could pay Workshop (my highly specialized service) to do it for you for a fraction of cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save 4-5 hours a week and just get the best consulting opportunities on the web delivered to your inbox! Starting at only $99/month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, using the steps outlined above you can generate steady client work just using job boards. This 1-on-1 outreach is powerful because you don’t have to rely on outside forces to win work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;now-that-you-have-hundreds-of-leads-at-your-fingertips-you-might-be-wondering-how-to-keep-track-of-it-all-thats-what-well-cover-next&quot;&gt;Now that you have hundreds of leads at your fingertips, you might be wondering how to keep track of it all. That’s what we’ll cover next:&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/finding-freelance-work-using-job-boards</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/finding-freelance-work-using-job-boards</guid>
        
        <category>finding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Managing leads</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently using gmail for pretty much everything. I did consider creating a spreadsheet as well to manage leads, but then thought, do I really need to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I actually do it, is by using the following tools;Pen and a small notebook. (List of potential clients, list of current clients). If a lead is unsuccessful, I simply cross it off. And I do this every 1 maybe 2 weeks. 2. I also label my leads in gmail, which I think is a good simple system to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t consider an actual web app or anything else to manage leads as majority of it is through email anyway. As well as that, personally, I’ve been trying to keep my list quite even, between current and potential clients. I don’t want to take too much on, I don’t apply to leads on a daily basis, or any at all if i’ve got 3 clients on. I only accept / apply for big budget work so my list of ‘currents’ are always between 1 and 4. I’d have no time for more so I wouldn’t be able to apply to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do have though is a spreadsheet for clients that pay for ongoing services. Other than that, email labels all the way man! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Adam Roberts&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/finding-managing-leads</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/finding-managing-leads</guid>
        
        <category>finding</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discounts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually give them a quote but let them know that if it’s outside their budget, I’m open to reducing the amount of hours or removing certain parts of the project in order to fit their budget range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the third, I usually ask for a ballpark. If I ask for the budget straight up - they usually ask me to come back with whatever I think it’s gonna cost. Instead I ask them for a range - What are you looking to invest? (Always use invest instead of “spend”); Are we talking 5000, 10000 or 50000$? Then they say, well it’s not 50000! Ok - is it closer to 10.000? Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great - now I know that $10,000 isnt out of the scope so placing myself at $4,000 would be stupid at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Anton Sten&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of an initial discussion, I ask, “What were you looking to spend on this project?” Some people like to get cute and refuse to answer, so I’ll press them on it but if they still won’t, I say, “Similar projects in the past have been between $10K and $20K” and gauge their reaction. I won’t waste my time writing anything down until I know what they want to spend and I’m sure it’s reasonable. Otherwise it’s like trying to sell a BMW to a hobo. Pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a redflag: “I haven’t worked on the CMS they’re using, and can’t really say how much time it would take me.” I would either budget an extra 20% to cover your learning curve or turn the project down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared by Workshop member Kurt Elster&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They key to lowering your rate and not coming off like you just inflate your prices for no reason is: don’t lower your rates without getting something in return. For example, you could add a few stipulations to working at a discounted rate, and make sure the client acknowledges and agrees before continuing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the client is blown away by your work, they agree:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will go back to your normal rate for all future projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They will refer you to 2 people who they know that might benefit from your services.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You will have rights to do a full case study and the client will provide any information you need.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The client will provide a testimonial upon completion of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obviously not all of those will apply, but you can add others that make more sense. I’d definitely keep #1 in there though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/winning-freelance-work-by-discounting</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/winning-freelance-work-by-discounting</guid>
        
        <category>winning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Follow ups</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been good at touching base. As a freelancer, this has cost me dearly. After all, you might not win business on the first contact with a prospect. It may take many touches to enter a business relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my follow up success stories is from a few years ago. I recently moved to Japan and met up with another software developer living in the area who I met on an online forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t keep in touch but 9 months later, I sent him an email out of the blue seeing how he was doing. He had started his own software consultancy in the meantime and replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“By the way: I’ve been searching for a developer to help me (short term) on some projects, and I totally forgot to ask you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, that relationship has resulted in $36,225.83 worth of business. Not bad for one follow up email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, Robert sent out an email to Shed subscribers titled “What should I do RIGHT NOW to get an inbox full of clients later?” He showed how he sets up a label for prospects to remind himself to follow up. I saw how this is a huge problem for myself and other freelancers. There could be thousands of dollars in opportunities sitting in your email but they end up slipping away unless you have an easy follow up reminder system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I built &lt;a href=&quot;https://touchingbase.io/&quot;&gt;https://touchingbase.io&lt;/a&gt; to help freelancers and consultants stay in touch with prospects and clients without the huge time hassle of setting up and using a CRM. I just launched it a couple weeks ago and have gotten some pretty good feedback on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, I’d be happy to answer them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared  by Workshop member Matt McCormick&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/winning-freelance-work-by-following-up</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/winning-freelance-work-by-following-up</guid>
        
        <category>winning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unrealistic budget</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eileen, I have some ideas on your RFP budget&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey Eileen,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your RFP says you need X, which I don’t recommend at for your budget. With your budget trying to get all X features would probably mean a lower quality developer who would do Y.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, here’s some of the features you mentioned which could get done at your budget, feature A, feature B, and feature C. These things are the core of what you’re looking for so you still get Z benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can I send over some more ideas for how to save on the project and still get what you need done?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/proposals-unrealistic-budget</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/proposals-unrealistic-budget</guid>
        
        <category>proposals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Suggesting a different solution</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Melinda,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking through your RFP, and noticed the following:
“A better system to find and remove duplicate records, including when participants initially sign up for trips and classes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that you don’t have to deal with that problem in the first place. The system should be build not allowing duplicates, that way you’ll spend no time removing them. I’m working with Ruby on Rails, and it is a problem unheard of there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you be interested in discussing it further? Would Friday 3pm CST work for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey Dmitry, wow! great email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially before the sentence “I’m working with Ruby on Rails, and it is a problem unheard of there.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d remove this part because it opens up a can of worms. as a reader it makes me think “why is it unheard of?” “what is ruby on rails?” “how much is switching my entire system to it going to cost me?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;instead i want to be thinking “ahhh i will no longer worry about duplicated at all” which is what your email was doing up until this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;did you hear back to this email?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://letsworkshop.com/advice/proposals-suggesting-a-different-solution</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://letsworkshop.com/advice/proposals-suggesting-a-different-solution</guid>
        
        <category>proposals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
